<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <language>en</language>
  <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
  <rcn>253601</rcn>
  <id>101107666</id>
  <acronym>WildEuro</acronym>
  <teaser>Standardized, large-scale monitoring programs are critical to track progress toward the biodiversity and sustainable goals identified by several international initiatives, including the European Green Deal. Yet, these programs are hard to establish, often because of limited...</teaser>
  <objective>Standardized, large-scale monitoring programs are critical to track progress toward the biodiversity and sustainable goals identified by several international initiatives, including the European Green Deal. Yet, these programs are hard to establish, often because of limited resources. International collaborations centered on data and knowledge sharing can fill this gap. The future fellow will gather and collate camera trap data collected across Europe in the past decade to quantify the impact on wildlife of the presence of humans and their domestic species in natural environments, at a fine temporal scale, and for the first time, across Europe. The mere presence of human and free-ranging dogs, cats, and livestock in natural environments might be detrimental to wildlife populations, with relatively unknown consequences on species’ persistence. This action aims at 1. quantifying the effects of human presence on mammals’ occupancy and activity; 2. assessing distribution and co-occurrence of free-ranging domestic animals and wildlife populations; 3. quantifying the effects of free-ranging domestic cats on urban and suburban mammal and bird communities. Along with leveraging publicly shared datasets, this action will build on and cement emerging European camera trap collaborations, and, thus, help establish the long-term, large-scale monitoring program that is paramount to tracking the status of terrestrial communities across Europe and informing European conservation policies. The future fellow will be hosted at the Max Planck Institute of Animal Behavior, a leading actor in the study of animal behavior and a strong promotor of European large-scale camera trap efforts. The future supervisor, Prof. Martin Wikelski, is a pioneer in leveraging international collaborations and technology to advance our understanding of animal decision-making processes across large scales. This action will greatly advance the fellow's expertise and establish her as an independent researcher.</objective>
  <title>Quantifying the landscape of fear: Collaborative camera trap networks to assess wildlife responses to activities of humans and free-ranging domestic species across Europe</title>
  <totalCost>0</totalCost>
  <ecMaxContribution>189687.36</ecMaxContribution>
  <startDate>2023-09-04</startDate>
  <endDate>2025-09-03</endDate>
  <ecSignatureDate>2023-04-11</ecSignatureDate>
  <duration>24</duration>
  <status>SIGNED</status>
  <keywords>camera trapping,  human-wildlife interactions,  eco-tourism,  disease spillover,  urban ecology,  collaborative networks,  free-ranging domestic species</keywords>
  <identifiers>
    <grantDoi>10.3030/101107666</grantDoi>
  </identifiers>
  <validation>
    <euroSciVoc>false</euroSciVoc>
  </validation>
  <sourceUpdateDate>2025-07-08 11:41:50</sourceUpdateDate>
  <contentCreationDate>2023-07-11 16:16:30</contentCreationDate>
  <contentUpdateDate>2025-08-11 10:19:26</contentUpdateDate>
  <lastUpdateDate>2025-11-03 09:43:33</lastUpdateDate>
  <relations>
    <associations>
      <article source="editorial" type="relatedArticle">
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>446139</rcn>
        <id>446139-assessing-how-humans-and-domestic-animals-harm-wildlife</id>
        <title>Assessing how humans and domestic animals harm wildlife</title>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-01-26 09:36:00</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/projectDescription</code>
              <title>Project description</title>
              <description>Article: description of linked project written by editorial team</description>
              <displayCode>/Project description</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/editorial</code>
              <title>CORDIS Editorial</title>
              <description>Written by CORDIS</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDIS Editorial</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </article>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedMasterCall">
        <rcn>55393</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedSubCall">
        <rcn>55393</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <organization netEcContribution="189687.36" totalCost="0" source="corda" order="1" ecContribution="189687.36" terminated="false" sme="false" type="coordinator">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1949732</rcn>
        <id>999990267</id>
        <vatNumber>DE129517720</vatNumber>
        <legalName>MAX-PLANCK-GESELLSCHAFT ZUR FORDERUNG DER WISSENSCHAFTEN EV</legalName>
        <shortName>MPG</shortName>
        <address>
          <street>HOFGARTENSTRASSE 8</street>
          <city>MUNCHEN</city>
          <postalCode>80539</postalCode>
          <country>DE</country>
          <postBox>000</postBox>
          <url>http://www.mpg.de</url>
          <geolocation>48.1411687,11.5822929</geolocation>
        </address>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="organizationActivityType" type="relatedOrganizationActivityType">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/REC</code>
              <title>Research Organisations</title>
              <displayCode>/Research Organisations</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <regions>
            <region type="relatedNutsCode">
              <name>München, Kreisfreie Stadt</name>
              <rcn>221782082</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE212</nutsCode>
              <parents>
                <region>
                  <name>Oberbayern</name>
                  <rcn>221782120</rcn>
                  <nutsCode>DE21</nutsCode>
                  <parents>
                    <region>
                      <name>Bayern</name>
                      <rcn>221784616</rcn>
                      <nutsCode>DE2</nutsCode>
                      <parents>
                        <region>
                          <name>Germany</name>
                          <rcn>221940264</rcn>
                          <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
                          <euCode>DE</euCode>
                          <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
                        </region>
                      </parents>
                    </region>
                  </parents>
                </region>
              </parents>
            </region>
            <region type="relatedRegion">
              <name>Germany</name>
              <rcn>221940264</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
              <euCode>DE</euCode>
              <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
            </region>
          </regions>
        </relations>
      </organization>
      <programme type="relatedLegalBasis" source="corda" uniqueProgrammePart="true">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>705729</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON.1.2</id>
        <code>HORIZON.1.2</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <pga>HORIZON.1.2</pga>
        <title>Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA)</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>705726</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON.1</code>
            <parent>
              <programme>
                <rcn>705725</rcn>
                <code>HORIZON</code>
              </programme>
            </parent>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/legalbasis</code>
              <title>Legal Basis</title>
              <description>Programme: Legal basis for research funding</description>
              <displayCode>/Legal Basis</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <programme type="relatedTopic" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>706018</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON_HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01-01</id>
        <code>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01-01</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <title>MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships 2022</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>20300</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON-Topics</code>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/topic</code>
              <title>Topic</title>
              <description>Programme: Part of the Commission work programme implementing legal basis</description>
              <displayCode>/Topic</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1379199</rcn>
        <id>101107666_249229_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>Long-term research presence mitigates hunting pressure and shapes mammal communities in the Congo Basin</title>
        <details>
          <authors>Nadia Balduccio, Mattia Bessone, Fabiola Iannarilli, Francesco Rovero, Barbara Fruth</authors>
          <journalNumber>312</journalNumber>
          <journalTitle>Biological Conservation</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages></publishedPages>
          <publishedYear>2025</publishedYear>
          <publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <issn>0006-3207</issn>
          <doi>10.1016/J.BIOCON.2025.111502</doi>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-10-28 03:20:27</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-10-30 11:26:21</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode>/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode>/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1379197</rcn>
        <id>101107666_249231_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>When the wild things are: Defining mammalian diel activity and plasticity</title>
        <details>
          <authors>Kadambari Devarajan, Mason Fidino, Zach J. Farris, Solny A. Adalsteinsson, Gabriel Andrade-Ponce, Julia L. Angstmann, Whitney Anthonysamy, Jesica Aquino, Addisu Asefa, Belen Avila, Larissa L. Bailey, Lyandra Maria de Sousa Barbosa, Marcela de Frias Barreto, Owain Barton, Chloe E. Bates, Mayara Guimarães Beltrão, Tori Bird, Elizabeth G. Biro, Francesco Bisi, Daniel Bohórquez, Mark Boyce, Justin S. Brashares, Grace Bullington, Phoebe Burns, Jessica Burr, Andrew R. Butler, Kendall L. Calhoun, Tien Trung Cao, Natalia Casado, Juan Camilo Cepeda-Duque, Jonathon D. Cepek, Adriano Garcia Chiarello, Merri Collins, Pedro Cordeiro-Estrela, Sebastian Costa, Giacomo Cremonesi, Bogdan Cristescu, Paula Cruz, Anna Carolina Figueiredo de Albuquerque, Carlos De Angelo, Cláudia Bueno de Campos, Liana Mara Mendes de Sena, Mario Di Bitetti, Douglas de Matos Dias, Duane Diefenbach, Tim S. Doherty, Thais P. dos Santos, Gabriela Teixeira Duarte, Timothy M. Eppley, John Erb, Carolina Franco Esteves, Bryn Evans, Maria L. M. Falcão, Hugo Fernandes-Ferreira, John R. Fieberg, Luiz Carlos Firmino de Souza Filho, Jason Fisher, Marie-Josee Fortin, George A. Gale, Travis Gallo, Laken S. Ganoe, Rony Garcia-Anleu, Kaitlyn M. Gaynor, Tiziana A. Gelmi-Candusso, Phillys N. Gichuru, Quimey Gomez, Austin M. Green, Luiza Neves Guimarães, Jeffrey D. Haight, Lavendar R. Harris, Zachary D. Hawn, Jordan Heiman, Huy Quoc Hoang, Sarah Huebner, Fabiola Iannarilli, María Eugenia Iezzi, Jacob S. Ivan, Kodi J. Jaspers, Mark J. Jordan, Jason Kamilar, Mamadou Kane, Mohammad Hosein Karimi, Marcella Kelly, Michel T. Kohl, William P. Kuvlesky, Andrew Ladle, Rachel N. Larson, Quy Tan Le, Duy Le, Van Son Le, Elizabeth W. Lehrer, Patrick E. Lendrum, Jesse Lewis, Andrés Link, Diego J. Lizcano, Jason V. Lombardi, Robert Long, Eva López-Tello, Camile Lugarini, David Lugo, Paula MacKay, Maria Madadi, Rodolfo Assis Magalhães, Seth B. Magle, Ludmila Hufnagel Regis Diniz Maia, Salvador Mandujano, Taisiia Marchenkova, Paulo Henrique Marinho, Laurie Marker, Julia Martinez Pardo, Adriano Martinoli, Rodrigo Lima Massara, Juliana Masseloux, Dina Matiukhina, Amy Mayer, Luis Mazariegos, Maureen R. McClung, Alex McInturff, Darby McPhail, Amy Mertl, Christopher R. Middaugh, David Miller, David Mills, Dale Miquelle, Vivianna Miritis, Remington J. Moll, Péter Molnár, Robert A. Montgomery, Toni Lyn Morelli, Alessio Mortelliti, Rachael I. Mueller, Anna S. Mukhacheva, Kayleigh Mullen, Asia Murphy, Vance Nepomuceno, Dusit Ngoprasert, An Nguyen, Thanh Van Nguyen, Van Thai Nguyen, Hoa Anh Nguyen Quang, Rob Nipko, Ana Clarissa Costa Nobre, Joseph Northrup, Megan A. Owen, Adriano Pereira Paglia, Meredith S. Palmer, Gabriela Palomo-Munoz, Lain E. Pardo, Chrystina Parks, Ana Maria de Oliveira Paschoal, Brent Patterson, Agustin Paviolo, Liba Pejchar, Mary E. Pendergast, Humberto L. Perotto-Baldivieso, Timofei Petrov, Mairi K. P. Poisson, Daiana Jeronimo Polli, Morteza Pourmirzai, Alexander Reebin, Katie R. Remine, Lindsey Rich, Christopher S. Richardson, Facundo Robino, Daniel G. Rocha, Fabiana Lopes Rocha, Flávio Henrique Guimarães Rodrigues, Adam T. Rohnke, Travis J. Ryan, Carmen M. Salsbury, Heather A. Sander, Nadia Maria da Cruz Santos-Cavalcante, Cagan H. Sekercioglu, Ivan Seryodkin, Dede Hendra Setiawan, Shabnam Shadloo, Mahsa Shahhosseini, Graeme Shannon, Catherine J. Shier, G. Bradley Smith, Tom Snyder, Rahel Sollmann, Kimberly L. Sparks, Kriangsak Sribuarod, Colleen C. St. Clair, Theodore Stankowich, Robert Steinmetz, Cassondra J. Stevenson, null Sunarto Sunarto, Thilina D. Surasinghe, Svetlana V. Sutyrina, Ronald R. Swaisgood, Atie Taktehrani, Kanchan Thapa, Matthew Thorton, Andrew Tilker, Mathias W. Tobler, Van Bang Tran, Jody Tucker, Russell C. Van Horn, Juan S. Vargas-Soto, Karen L. Velásquez-C, Jan Venter, Eduardo M. Venticinque, Stijn Verschueren, Erin Wampole, Darcy J Watchorn, Oliver R. Wearn, Katherine C.B. Weiss, Alejandro Welschen, Febri Anggriawan Widodo, Jacque Williamson, And</authors>
          <journalNumber>11</journalNumber>
          <journalTitle>Science Advances</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages></publishedPages>
          <publishedYear>2025</publishedYear>
          <publisher>American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS)</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <issn>2375-2548</issn>
          <doi>10.1126/SCIADV.ADO3843</doi>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-10-28 03:20:27</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-10-30 11:26:21</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode>/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode>/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1019912</rcn>
        <id>101107666_1_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Data management plan</title>
        <description>The Data Management Plan describes the data management life cycle for all data sets that will be collected processed or generated by the action It is a document describing what data will be collected processed or generated and following what methodology and standards whether and how this data will be shared andor made open and how it will be curated and preserved</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2023-12-21 13:23:34</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2023-12-22 11:42:16</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable" represents="project">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
              <id>aedbd1a5a4f9ffef77cf4642afee1881</id>
              <physUrl>https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e503461428&amp;appId=PPGMS</physUrl>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode>/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/DMP</code>
              <title>Data Management Plan</title>
              <displayCode>/Data Management Plan</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1379198</rcn>
        <id>101107666_249230_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>Methods in Ecology and Evolution</title>
        <details>
          <authors>Martin Wikelski; Michael Quetting; John Bates; Tanya Berger‐Wolf; Gil Bohrer; Luca Börger; Taylor Chapple; Margaret C. Crofoot; Sarah C. Davidson; Dina K. N. Dechmann; Diego Ellis‐Soto; Elizabeth R. Ellwood; Wolfgang Fiedler; Andrea Flack; Barbara Fruth; Novella Franconi; Rasmus Worsøe Havmøller; Julian Hirt; Nigel E. Hussey; Fabiola Iannarilli; Matthias Landwehr; Maximilian E. Müller; Thomas Mueller; Uschi Mueller; Ruth Y. Oliver; Jesko Partecke; Ivan Pokrovsky; Liya Pokrovskaya; Dustin R. Rubenstein; Christian Rutz; Kamran Safi; Andrea Santangeli; O. Louis van Schalkwyk; Ana M. M. Sequeira; Sherub Sherub; Tharmalingam Ramesh; Pauli Viljoen; Kaja A. Wasik; Timm A. Wild; Scott Yanco; Roland Kays</authors>
          <journalNumber></journalNumber>
          <journalTitle>Methods in Ecology and Evolution</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages></publishedPages>
          <publishedYear>2024</publishedYear>
          <publisher>John Wiley and Sons Inc.</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <issn>2041-210X</issn>
          <doi>10.1111/2041-210X.14407</doi>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-10-28 03:20:27</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-10-30 11:26:21</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode>/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode>/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
    </associations>
    <categories>
      <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/project</code>
        <title>Project</title>
        <description>Project factsheets</description>
        <displayCode>/Project</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/25/73/453/58525161/44113014</code>
        <title>optical sensors</title>
        <displayCode>/engineering and technology/electrical engineering, electronic engineering, information engineering/electronic engineering/sensors/optical sensors</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/49/335/1009</code>
        <title>ecosystems</title>
        <displayCode>/natural sciences/biological sciences/ecology/ecosystems</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/27/83/501/507</code>
        <title>animal husbandry</title>
        <displayCode>/agricultural sciences/animal and dairy science/domestic animals/animal husbandry</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/49/345/1045</code>
        <title>mammalogy</title>
        <displayCode>/natural sciences/biological sciences/zoology/mammalogy</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="40">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/digitalAgenda</code>
        <title>Digital agenda</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development of digital technologies and the digitisation of the economy and society (known as ‘Digital transition’).</description>
        <displayCode>/Digital agenda</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="100">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/cleanAir</code>
        <title>Clean air</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the clean air policy (National Emission Ceiling Directive) aiming to improve ambient air quality and tackle air pollution, to protect the environment and human health.</description>
        <displayCode>/Clean air</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="40">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/ai</code>
        <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development and deployment of AI-based technologies and solutions. Projects that develop AI-tools as part of their research method are included</description>
        <displayCode>/Artificial intelligence</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="100">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/climate</code>
        <title>Climate action</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to both mitigating climate change (e.g., contributions to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions) and adapting to climate change by building resilience (e.g., regarding floods, droughts, spatial planning and better governance, adaptation to changing climate in value chains, etc.).</description>
        <displayCode>/Climate action</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="40">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/biodiversity</code>
        <title>Biodiversity</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to Europe’s biodiversity’s path to recovery including species protection, ecosystem conservation, and habitat rehabilitation, all essential for resilience in climate adaptation and addressing ecosystem services but also environmental crime and the health-environment connection.</description>
        <displayCode>/Biodiversity</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="projectFundingSchemeCategory" type="relatedProjectFundingSchemeCategory">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <code>/HORIZON-TMA-MSCA-PF-EF</code>
        <title>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</title>
        <description>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</description>
        <displayCode>/HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/corda</code>
        <title>CORDA</title>
        <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
        <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
      </category>
    </categories>
  </relations>
</project>