<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <language>en</language>
  <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
  <rcn>239386</rcn>
  <id>101068378</id>
  <acronym>NeuroProClick</acronym>
  <teaser>Neurodegenerative disorders are characterised by the progressive deterioration and loss of certain neuronal populations. Distinct clinical features are associated with different diseases, but common fundamental processes have been identified. One example of this is injury via...</teaser>
  <objective>Neurodegenerative disorders are characterised by the progressive deterioration and loss of certain neuronal populations. Distinct clinical features are associated with different diseases, but common fundamental processes have been identified. One example of this is injury via oxidative stress. The production of oxidative species is linked to mitochondrial dysfunction and inflammation, which have been demonstrated to occur early in these disorders. Identifying the proteins that are involved in the response to these species is of critical importance to understanding these diseases. This will provide opportunities to identify novel biomarkers and develop treatments that are effective at these early stages. 
The use of genetic code expansion to functionalise proteins with clickable amino acids is an emerging protein engineering technology with many potential applications in neurobiology. Recently, it has been demonstrated that any of the 20 natural amino acids can be replaced with a non-canonical amino acid (ncAA) on a proteome-wide scale. However, the application of this technology in complex cells, such as neurons, is still in its infancy. I aim to establish a novel proteome-wide ncAA incorporation methodology to monitor changes in the neuronal proteome in response to oxidative injury. This will be achieved using ncAAs that have been optimised for an inverse-electron-demand Diels-Alder click reaction, which is highly biorthogonal and has extremely rapid kinetics. Adding a clickable biotin handle will facilitate protein enrichment in a highly time-resolved manner. Subsequent proteomic analysis will be applied to identify changes within the whole proteome or subsets of the proteome. Monitoring changes in protein expression in this way will provide valuable information about neurodegenerative disorders and allow for precise investigations of potential new drug targets and biomarkers.</objective>
  <title>Protein-engineering based approach to detect oxidative stress-induced changes in the neuronal proteome</title>
  <totalCost>0</totalCost>
  <ecMaxContribution>173847.36</ecMaxContribution>
  <startDate>2022-08-01</startDate>
  <endDate>2024-07-31</endDate>
  <ecSignatureDate>2022-06-10</ecSignatureDate>
  <duration>24</duration>
  <status>CLOSED</status>
  <keywords>Quantitative proteomics/ Genetic code expansion/ Neurons/ Oxidative injury/ Click chemistry</keywords>
  <identifiers>
    <grantDoi>10.3030/101068378</grantDoi>
  </identifiers>
  <validation>
    <euroSciVoc>false</euroSciVoc>
  </validation>
  <sourceUpdateDate>2024-04-05 14:00:07</sourceUpdateDate>
  <contentCreationDate>2022-08-05 19:16:47</contentCreationDate>
  <contentUpdateDate>2024-04-05 14:00:07</contentUpdateDate>
  <lastUpdateDate>2025-11-26 10:33:03</lastUpdateDate>
  <relations>
    <associations>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedMasterCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedSubCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <organization netEcContribution="173847.36" totalCost="0" source="corda" order="1" ecContribution="173847.36" terminated="false" sme="false" type="coordinator">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1905979</rcn>
        <id>999991916</id>
        <vatNumber>DE812383453</vatNumber>
        <legalName>EBERHARD KARLS UNIVERSITAET TUEBINGEN</legalName>
        <shortName>UT</shortName>
        <address>
          <street>GESCHWISTER-SCHOLL-PLATZ</street>
          <city>Tuebingen</city>
          <postalCode>72074</postalCode>
          <country>DE</country>
          <postBox>N/A</postBox>
          <url>http://www.uni-tuebingen.de</url>
          <geolocation>48.52441205,9.05972173269931</geolocation>
        </address>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="organizationActivityType" type="relatedOrganizationActivityType">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/HES</code>
              <title>Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</title>
              <displayCode>/Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <regions>
            <region type="relatedNutsCode">
              <name>Tübingen, Landkreis</name>
              <rcn>221778178</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE142</nutsCode>
              <parents>
                <region>
                  <name>Tübingen</name>
                  <rcn>221778216</rcn>
                  <nutsCode>DE14</nutsCode>
                  <parents>
                    <region>
                      <name>Baden-Württemberg</name>
                      <rcn>221780520</rcn>
                      <nutsCode>DE1</nutsCode>
                      <parents>
                        <region>
                          <name>Germany</name>
                          <rcn>221940264</rcn>
                          <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
                          <euCode>DE</euCode>
                          <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
                        </region>
                      </parents>
                    </region>
                  </parents>
                </region>
              </parents>
            </region>
            <region type="relatedRegion">
              <name>Germany</name>
              <rcn>221940264</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
              <euCode>DE</euCode>
              <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
            </region>
          </regions>
        </relations>
      </organization>
      <programme type="relatedTopic" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>706003</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON_HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</id>
        <code>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <title>MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships 2021</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>20300</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON-Topics</code>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/topic</code>
              <title>Topic</title>
              <description>Programme: Part of the Commission work programme implementing legal basis</description>
              <displayCode>/Topic</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <programme type="relatedLegalBasis" source="corda" uniqueProgrammePart="true">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>705729</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON.1.2</id>
        <code>HORIZON.1.2</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <pga>HORIZON.1.2</pga>
        <title>Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA)</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>705726</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON.1</code>
            <parent>
              <programme>
                <rcn>705725</rcn>
                <code>HORIZON</code>
              </programme>
            </parent>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/legalbasis</code>
              <title>Legal Basis</title>
              <description>Programme: Legal basis for research funding</description>
              <displayCode>/Legal Basis</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1142261</rcn>
        <id>101068378_3_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Communication, Dissemination &amp; Outreach Plan</title>
        <description>The primary goal of this research project is to develop a novel, translatable methodology that can be used to monitor changes within the proteome of neuronal cells. This will be a valuable research tool and therefore the main target of our dissemination will be other scientists. We will disseminate results in peer reviewed scientific journals and at international conferences. The host laboratory has a strong publication history, including making research papers available on open access preprint servers whenever possible. We intend to continue to disseminate our results in this way, following the open science practices. We will put relevant raw data, such as proteomic data and microscopy images, in online open access databases. The skills and protocols will be passed on to researchers within the host laboratory during mentoring activities. Considering its interdisciplinary nature, our results will be of interest to both neuroscientists and chemical biologists. We have therefore identified international chemical biology conferences such as ‘Chemical Biology 2022’ (EMBL Heidelberg) and ‘Chemical Biology Ireland 2022’ (Dublin) as opportunities to disseminate our results to chemical biologists. The Gordon Research Conference ‘Emerging Technologies to Study Nervous System Development, Function and Neurological Disease 2022’ conference will be an opportunity to present our results to neuroscientists. We have also identified the annual ‘International Conference on Molecular and Cellular Neurobiology’ as an opportunity to disseminate our results in 2023. We also plan to communicate our research with the general public to highlight the importance of developing new interdisciplinary techniques for understanding neurological disorders. Tübingen is home to the annual ‘Tübingen Fenster fur Forschung’. Here lay people have an opportunity to attend  courses, seminars and receive laboratory tours in Tübingen. As a laboratory, we plan to participate in this event to promote our research and the benefits of MSCA funding. We will also use social media  to promote our research online by posting links to open access versions of our research and any  presentations or public outreach events. This can be achieved using the EKUT and the Tübingen Neuro Campus accounts on YouTube (UkTimTV), Twitter (@uni_tue, @TueNeuroCampus) and Facebook (UniTübingen). This type of communication will also be carried out via personal accounts on LinkedIn, ResearchGate and Twitter. Based on my previous outreach experience, we will tailor our online content depending on the platform and target audience of the communication.</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-07-30 10:32:54</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-08-06 15:04:24</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
              <id>e66ff758710a3873939710674f09fc4b</id>
              <physUrl>https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e51007225c&amp;appId=PPGMS</physUrl>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode>/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/R</code>
              <title>Documents, reports</title>
              <displayCode>/Documents, reports</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1213780</rcn>
        <id>101068378_PSHORIZON</id>
        <title>Periodic Reporting for period 1 - NeuroProClick (Protein-engineering based approach to detect oxidative stress-induced changes in the neuronal proteome)</title>
        <description>periodic</description>
        <teaser>Neurodegenerative disorders are characterised by the disruption of key cellular processes and neuronal loss. Injury via oxidative stress is also associated with the progression of these diseases. Identifying changes within neuronal cells at specific time points will help us...</teaser>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-11-25 04:23:04</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-12-02 12:10:14</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/pubsum</code>
              <title>Report Summary</title>
              <description>Result: Publishable summary (FP7 SESAM) and Summary for publication (H2020 SyGMa)</description>
              <displayCode>/Report Summary</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>976525</rcn>
        <id>101068378_1_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Data Management Plan</title>
        <description>All research data will be managed following the FAIR guidelines Image data generated by microscopy and imaging of gels and gel membranes for western blotting will be saved as TIFF files Metadata will be recorded according to Recommended Metadata for Biological Images REMBI guidelines Files will be named following a consistent format with unique identifiers The unique identifier will correspond to an experiment created in an online lab book which will be created using the same name The raw data will be stored on a password protected server which will be accessible to all lab members Links to this server and exact details of the storage location will be recorded in an online lab book which also contains all details about the execution of the experiments Raw microscopy data from published scientific articles will be made available on the BioImage archive which has adopted REMBI as a standard This can be accessed easily online and images will be in a format compatible with free software such as ImageJ Any relevant proteomic data will be stored in databases such as the PRIDE in a format that can be accessed with open access software such as MaxQuant and Perseus All this data will be identified on this repository with a DOI of corresponding publications Both repositories are free so there will be no additional costs associated</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2023-02-06 07:34:12</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2023-09-29 11:41:31</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable" represents="project">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
              <id>5da8845647681fbe8499469832a7aad1</id>
              <physUrl>https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e5f71521e6&amp;appId=PPGMS</physUrl>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode>/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/DMP</code>
              <title>Data Management Plan</title>
              <displayCode>/Data Management Plan</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
    </associations>
    <categories>
      <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/project</code>
        <title>Project</title>
        <description>Project factsheets</description>
        <displayCode>/Project</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/49/327</code>
        <title>neurobiology</title>
        <displayCode>/natural sciences/biological sciences/neurobiology</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/49/315/997/1613/1815</code>
        <title>proteomics</title>
        <displayCode>/natural sciences/biological sciences/biochemistry/biomolecules/proteins/proteomics</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/digitalAgenda</code>
        <title>Digital agenda</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development of digital technologies and the digitisation of the economy and society (known as ‘Digital transition’).</description>
        <displayCode>/Digital agenda</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/cleanAir</code>
        <title>Clean air</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the clean air policy (National Emission Ceiling Directive) aiming to improve ambient air quality and tackle air pollution, to protect the environment and human health.</description>
        <displayCode>/Clean air</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/ai</code>
        <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development and deployment of AI-based technologies and solutions. Projects that develop AI-tools as part of their research method are included</description>
        <displayCode>/Artificial intelligence</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/climate</code>
        <title>Climate action</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to both mitigating climate change (e.g., contributions to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions) and adapting to climate change by building resilience (e.g., regarding floods, droughts, spatial planning and better governance, adaptation to changing climate in value chains, etc.).</description>
        <displayCode>/Climate action</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/biodiversity</code>
        <title>Biodiversity</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to Europe’s biodiversity’s path to recovery including species protection, ecosystem conservation, and habitat rehabilitation, all essential for resilience in climate adaptation and addressing ecosystem services but also environmental crime and the health-environment connection.</description>
        <displayCode>/Biodiversity</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="projectFundingSchemeCategory" type="relatedProjectFundingSchemeCategory">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <code>/HORIZON-TMA-MSCA-PF-EF</code>
        <title>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</title>
        <description>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</description>
        <displayCode>/HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/corda</code>
        <title>CORDA</title>
        <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
        <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
      </category>
    </categories>
  </relations>
</project>