<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <language>en</language>
  <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
  <rcn>242311</rcn>
  <id>101066960</id>
  <acronym>TLTL</acronym>
  <teaser>Towards demonstrating new electrically pumped lasers based on the emerge metal halide perovskite, it is necessary to sandwich the perovskite thin film into transport layers for the integration of electrical devices. However, it is challenging to maintain the low threshold when...</teaser>
  <objective>Towards demonstrating new electrically pumped lasers based on the emerge metal halide perovskite, it is necessary to sandwich the perovskite thin film into transport layers for the integration of electrical devices. However, it is challenging to maintain the low threshold when introducing transport layers. The appearance of perovskite/transport layer interfaces, which is absent in most optically pumped perovskite lasers, is even considered as detrimental factors to lasing actions. By carefully integrating the perovskite films into electrical device structures, though reaching very high injection current densities (&gt; 1 kA/cm2), often fails to realize lasing actions. The next urgent milestone towards electrically pumped perovskite lasers would be realization of low threshold when incorporating transport layers. This project has the goal to reduce lasing threshold of perovskite devices through transport layer engineering, a strategy which is the key step towards realizing perovskite lasers. I will take a holistic approach, where two novel strategies are proposed independently. Two objectives will contribute to solve an important challenge on interface engineering towards electrically pumped perovskite lasers.

Objective 1: To reduce the surface recombination loss for low threshold. I will seek effective approaches to passivate perovskite films through transport layer engineering, leading to suppressed radiative and nonradiative recombination loss at perovskite boundaries.

Objective 2: To reduce recombination loss channels caused by hot carriers for low threshold. I will achieve this objective by hot carrier management via selective transport layers, aiming at suppressing hot carrier injection and facilitating hot carrier cooling.</objective>
  <title>Transport layer engineering towards lower threshold for perovskite lasers</title>
  <totalCost>0</totalCost>
  <ecMaxContribution>222727.68</ecMaxContribution>
  <startDate>2022-09-15</startDate>
  <endDate>2024-09-14</endDate>
  <ecSignatureDate>2022-09-28</ecSignatureDate>
  <duration>24</duration>
  <status>TERMINATED</status>
  <keywords>transport layer engineering,  low threshold,  hot carrier management,  reduce recombination loss,  perovskite lasers</keywords>
  <identifiers>
    <grantDoi>10.3030/101066960</grantDoi>
  </identifiers>
  <validation>
    <euroSciVoc>false</euroSciVoc>
  </validation>
  <sourceUpdateDate>2024-07-22 01:50:45</sourceUpdateDate>
  <contentCreationDate>2022-10-06 17:59:41</contentCreationDate>
  <contentUpdateDate>2023-03-10 22:09:28</contentUpdateDate>
  <lastUpdateDate>2025-09-19 14:49:03</lastUpdateDate>
  <terminationDate>2024-09-01 00:00:00</terminationDate>
  <relations>
    <associations>
      <article source="editorial" type="relatedArticle">
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>438516</rcn>
        <id>438516-shining-a-new-light-on-perovskite-lasers</id>
        <title>Shining a new light on perovskite lasers</title>
        <contentUpdateDate>2023-02-27 16:58:02</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/projectDescription</code>
              <title>Project description</title>
              <description>Article: description of linked project written by editorial team</description>
              <displayCode>/Project description</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/editorial</code>
              <title>CORDIS Editorial</title>
              <description>Written by CORDIS</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDIS Editorial</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </article>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedMasterCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedSubCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <organization netEcContribution="222727.68" totalCost="0" source="corda" order="1" ecContribution="222727.68" terminated="false" sme="false" type="coordinator">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1949125</rcn>
        <id>999852236</id>
        <vatNumber>SE202100309601</vatNumber>
        <legalName>LINKOPINGS UNIVERSITET</legalName>
        <shortName>LIU</shortName>
        <address>
          <street>CAMPUS VALLA</street>
          <city>Linkoping</city>
          <postalCode>581 83</postalCode>
          <country>SE</country>
          <postBox>N/A</postBox>
          <url>http://www.liu.se</url>
          <geolocation>58.4004423,15.5765096</geolocation>
        </address>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="organizationActivityType" type="relatedOrganizationActivityType">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/HES</code>
              <title>Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</title>
              <displayCode>/Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <regions>
            <region type="relatedNutsCode">
              <name>Östergötlands län</name>
              <rcn>473436291</rcn>
              <nutsCode>SE123</nutsCode>
              <parents>
                <region>
                  <name>Östra Mellansverige</name>
                  <rcn>473436328</rcn>
                  <nutsCode>SE12</nutsCode>
                  <parents>
                    <region>
                      <name>Östra Sverige</name>
                      <rcn>473438760</rcn>
                      <nutsCode>SE1</nutsCode>
                      <parents>
                        <region>
                          <name>Sweden</name>
                          <rcn>473598504</rcn>
                          <nutsCode>SE</nutsCode>
                          <euCode>SE</euCode>
                          <isoCode>SE</isoCode>
                        </region>
                      </parents>
                    </region>
                  </parents>
                </region>
              </parents>
            </region>
            <region type="relatedRegion">
              <name>Sweden</name>
              <rcn>473598504</rcn>
              <nutsCode>SE</nutsCode>
              <euCode>SE</euCode>
              <isoCode>SE</isoCode>
            </region>
          </regions>
        </relations>
      </organization>
      <programme type="relatedTopic" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>706003</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON_HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</id>
        <code>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <title>MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships 2021</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>20300</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON-Topics</code>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/topic</code>
              <title>Topic</title>
              <description>Programme: Part of the Commission work programme implementing legal basis</description>
              <displayCode>/Topic</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <programme type="relatedLegalBasis" source="corda" uniqueProgrammePart="true">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>705729</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON.1.2</id>
        <code>HORIZON.1.2</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <pga>HORIZON.1.2</pga>
        <title>Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA)</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>705726</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON.1</code>
            <parent>
              <programme>
                <rcn>705725</rcn>
                <code>HORIZON</code>
              </programme>
            </parent>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/legalbasis</code>
              <title>Legal Basis</title>
              <description>Programme: Legal basis for research funding</description>
              <displayCode>/Legal Basis</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1227727</rcn>
        <id>101066960_3_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Communication, Dissemination &amp; Exploitation Plan</title>
        <description>For the world-wide scientific community, I will actively participate in the discussions with several top scientists among the host supervisor’s collaborators, via sharing my research updates and my future plans. The target scientists cover both national and international ones, including Prof. Olle Inganäs (a leading scientist in polymer-based solar cells), Prof. Arkady Yartsev (an expert in ultrafast laser technology), Prof. Richard Friend (a pioneer in halide perovskite materials), Prof. Wolfgang Tress (a top scientist in device physics of perovskite devices) and Prof. Jianpu Wang (a pioneer in highly efficient perovskite LEDs). Through presenting my results and ideas, I can get instant feedback from them. The form of discussion can be either individual meeting or joint group meeting. On one hand, possible collaborations regarding my research will be easily established, which can involve more top researchers into my project. On the other hand, presenting my results to these top scientists will benefit for the worldwide dissemination. In addition to the discussions, I will also actively participate in some international conferences at least twice a year, such as PSCO (International Conference on Perovskite Solar Cells and Optoelectronics, annual coference in the field of perovskite) and MRS (materials research society, joint meeting in the field of material science). My preliminary results will be shared in the form of talks or posters. As expected, at least two sucessful designs of lowering threshold towards perovskite electrically pumped light amplification will be organized into papers, which are supposed to submitted to high-impact journals such as Nature and Science family. This will not only help me to build international reputation and networks in academia, but also enhance the academic impact of the host organization in perovskite lasers. For the young students and public, the host university has traditional annual activities facing the public, such as Summer Week, Popular Science Week and Open Door Days. In the Summer Week, I will introduce perovskites and laser technologies to high-school students. I will also give lectures to the general public at the Popular Science Week and take part in the annual Open Door Days to impart basic knowledge of lasers to college students. In addition, I will also try to provide more people with the science and technology related knowledge by using public social media, such as Linked-In, Facebook and YouTube.I will file patents based on any patentable results prior to scientific publications. In addition, the advisors at LiU Innovation will give me supports. They will provide me with counselling free of charge in areas such as patent, start-up and financing. I will closely contact with the LiU innovation office to seek advice regarding potential commercialization of the results that originate from this project, and start a business whenever possible. In Sweden, universities own the intellectual property arises from Horizon 2020 projects by signing an agreement with the researcher. Therefore, intellectual property from this project will be owned by LiU.Scientific impacts: This project focuses on reducing lasing threshold of perovskite devices via transport layer engineering, which involves several novel designs, such as HC management and Rashba splitting tuning. These designs can revolutionize the field of perovskite lasers by providing new ideas to the realization of electrically pumped perovskite lasers. The impact of new device optimization strategies will go vastly beyond the field of perovskite lasers, and can be envisioned to be used for other perovskite optoelectronic applications, such as lightning and solar cells. Technological impacts: Low-cost solution-processed semiconductors provide new opportunities to significantly expand the applications of lasers. On one hand, low-cost and scalable deposition can meet increasing demand of using lasers in consumer electronics.</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-12-02 09:44:48</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-12-09 12:38:15</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
              <id>41fba34788de20a5368bb345cf3988d9</id>
              <physUrl>https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e5113b8b3e&amp;appId=PPGMS</physUrl>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode>/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/R</code>
              <title>Documents, reports</title>
              <displayCode>/Documents, reports</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1227719</rcn>
        <id>101066960_1_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Data Management Plan</title>
        <description>The research data management will obey the rule of the host university (Linkoping University). Firstly, all my experimental procedures, including the receipes for materials synthesis, device structures or other fabrication details will be recorded in my individual notebook. It enables me and my colleagues to repeat my experients easily. The notebook will be shared within the host supervisor’s group when necessary and a copy will be left after the project. Secondly, all the digital data will be uploaded in a public hard-drive disk with detailed note information. The note information must ensure that anyone else with basic scientific training can know and repeate the data results. These data will be saved in three places: my personal computer, group public computer and group public disk. With the permission from host supervisor and me, the original data will be accessible for all the group members or related collaborators. If possible, some usueful methods towards realizing electrically pumped lasers would generate patents.</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-12-02 09:44:48</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-12-09 12:38:14</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
              <id>b9ac4646bef4deaaca9ac50f576d47a8</id>
              <physUrl>https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e5113b9842&amp;appId=PPGMS</physUrl>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode>/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/R</code>
              <title>Documents, reports</title>
              <displayCode>/Documents, reports</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1213178</rcn>
        <id>101066960_51975_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>Transport Layer Engineering Toward Lower Threshold for Perovskite Lasers</title>
        <details>
          <authors>Jia Zhang, Jiajun Qin, Weidong Cai, Yipeng Tang, Huotian Zhang, Tong Wang, Artem Bakulin, Bin Hu, Xiao-Ke Liu, Feng Gao</authors>
          <journalNumber></journalNumber>
          <journalTitle>Advanced Materials</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages></publishedPages>
          <publishedYear>2023</publishedYear>
          <publisher>United Nations Industrial Developement Organization</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <issn>0935-9648</issn>
          <doi>10.1002/adma.202300922</doi>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-08-26 03:59:49</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-11-26 16:24:39</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode>/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode>/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1038809</rcn>
        <id>101066960_15391_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>From optical pumping to electrical pumping: the threshold overestimation in metal halide perovskites</title>
        <details>
          <authors>Jiajun Qin; Yang Tang; Jia Zhang; Tangyao Shen; Max Karlsson; Tiankai Zhang; Weidong Cai; Lei Shi; Wei-Xin Ni; Feng Gao</authors>
          <journalTitle>Materials Horizon</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages></publishedPages>
          <publishedYear>2023</publishedYear>
          <publisher>Materials Horizons</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <issn>2051-6347</issn>
          <doi>10.1039/d2mh01382g</doi>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-08-26 03:59:49</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-02-06 08:57:08</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode>/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode>/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1232971</rcn>
        <id>101066960_PSHORIZON</id>
        <title>Periodic Reporting for period 1 - TLTL (Transport layer engineering towards lower threshold for perovskite lasers)</title>
        <description>periodic</description>
        <teaser>Backgrounds:Electrically driven surface-emitting lasers, with an output of a coherent light source, are a fast-growing technology in various applications such as information transmission, medical treatment, and 3D sensing.  However, the current successful industrial...</teaser>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-12-18 16:03:19</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-12-18 16:03:19</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <associations>
            <webItem type="relatedResultAttachment" source="corda">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>en,any</availableLanguages>
              <uri>/docs/results/horizon/101066/101066960_PS/msca-figure-2.jpeg</uri>
              <mimetype>image/jpeg</mimetype>
              <size>62464</size>
            </webItem>
            <webItem type="relatedResultAttachment" source="corda">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>en,any</availableLanguages>
              <uri>/docs/results/horizon/101066/101066960_PS/msca-figure-1.jpeg</uri>
              <mimetype>image/jpeg</mimetype>
              <size>81920</size>
            </webItem>
          </associations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/pubsum</code>
              <title>Report Summary</title>
              <description>Result: Publishable summary (FP7 SESAM) and Summary for publication (H2020 SyGMa)</description>
              <displayCode>/Report Summary</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
    </associations>
    <categories>
      <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/project</code>
        <title>Project</title>
        <description>Project factsheets</description>
        <displayCode>/Project</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/43/251/745</code>
        <title>laser physics</title>
        <displayCode>/natural sciences/physical sciences/optics/laser physics</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/digitalAgenda</code>
        <title>Digital agenda</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development of digital technologies and the digitisation of the economy and society (known as ‘Digital transition’).</description>
        <displayCode>/Digital agenda</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/cleanAir</code>
        <title>Clean air</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the clean air policy (National Emission Ceiling Directive) aiming to improve ambient air quality and tackle air pollution, to protect the environment and human health.</description>
        <displayCode>/Clean air</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/ai</code>
        <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development and deployment of AI-based technologies and solutions. Projects that develop AI-tools as part of their research method are included</description>
        <displayCode>/Artificial intelligence</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/climate</code>
        <title>Climate action</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to both mitigating climate change (e.g., contributions to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions) and adapting to climate change by building resilience (e.g., regarding floods, droughts, spatial planning and better governance, adaptation to changing climate in value chains, etc.).</description>
        <displayCode>/Climate action</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/biodiversity</code>
        <title>Biodiversity</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to Europe’s biodiversity’s path to recovery including species protection, ecosystem conservation, and habitat rehabilitation, all essential for resilience in climate adaptation and addressing ecosystem services but also environmental crime and the health-environment connection.</description>
        <displayCode>/Biodiversity</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="projectFundingSchemeCategory" type="relatedProjectFundingSchemeCategory">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <code>/HORIZON-TMA-MSCA-PF-EF</code>
        <title>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</title>
        <description>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</description>
        <displayCode>/HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/corda</code>
        <title>CORDA</title>
        <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
        <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
      </category>
    </categories>
  </relations>
</project>