<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <language>en</language>
  <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
  <rcn>240286</rcn>
  <id>101066396</id>
  <acronym>PLOBOT</acronym>
  <teaser>The 1966 sci-fi film, Fantastic Voyage, portrayed a scientist who miniaturized a submarine to enter his body to remove a blood clot. It is only recently that scientists have been able to assemble microrobots from scratch to autonomously move and perform complex tasks, such as...</teaser>
  <objective>The 1966 sci-fi film, Fantastic Voyage, portrayed a scientist who miniaturized a submarine to enter his body to remove a blood clot. It is only recently that scientists have been able to assemble microrobots from scratch to autonomously move and perform complex tasks, such as catching and delivering cargo, and/or performing chemical reactions. The bots use energy from their surroundings or from an external stimulus, and turn it into motion. Light-driven motion in photocatalytic robots is exceptionally appealing as it allows actuation and control by using an external free energy source i.e., sun and enhancement of chemical reactions due to two effects: self-generated micro-mixing effect and constant surface refreshment, giving place to new chemical reactions ‘on-the-fly’. Yet, the reported photocatalytic bots up to date are so slow that their speed can be confused with Brownian motion. This project seeks to combine two approaches for the first time to enhance the efficiency and speed of light-driven bots: Lorentz force as an ultrafast motion mechanism and plasmonic effects for bettering light harvesting. A novel system will be introduced in which the robot’s motion based on the magnetohydrodynamic convection effect is triggered by visible light and can pursue desired reactions (degradation of organic wastes and hydrogen generation). By leveraging the host’s fundamental photophysical approach in nanoplasmonic design and my interdisciplinary angle on microrobots and energy field, the results are expected to bring knowledge gain for the microrobot field, and possibly a long-term impact on Europe’s solar technological innovations. The project‘s training comprises transferrable (leadership and communication) and technical skills development (bridging a knowledge gap in photophysics), to advance my career as a future group leader in Europe with an unorthodox research angle combining photo/electrochemistry and microrobots for alternative energy and environmental solutions.</objective>
  <title>Autonomous Plasmon-Enhanced Photocatalytic Microrobots Powered by Lorentz Force</title>
  <keywords>Microrobots, nanoplasmonics, photocatalysis, Light-driven reactions, autonomous motion</keywords>
  <totalCost>0</totalCost>
  <ecMaxContribution>173847.36</ecMaxContribution>
  <startDate>2022-12-01</startDate>
  <endDate>2024-12-31</endDate>
  <ecSignatureDate>2022-07-07</ecSignatureDate>
  <duration>25</duration>
  <status>SIGNED</status>
  <identifiers>
    <grantDoi>10.3030/101066396</grantDoi>
  </identifiers>
  <validation>
    <euroSciVoc>false</euroSciVoc>
  </validation>
  <sourceUpdateDate>2025-03-14 10:51:11</sourceUpdateDate>
  <contentCreationDate readOnly="true">2022-08-26 15:32:46</contentCreationDate>
  <contentUpdateDate>2022-08-26 15:32:43</contentUpdateDate>
  <lastUpdateDate readOnly="true">2025-09-19 14:48:31</lastUpdateDate>
  <relations>
    <associations>
      <article source="editorial" type="relatedArticle">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>436966</rcn>
        <id>436966-enhancing-the-speed-and-efficiency-of-photocatalytic-microbots</id>
        <title>Enhancing the speed and efficiency of photocatalytic microbots</title>
        <contentUpdateDate>2022-11-07 17:18:00</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/projectDescription</code>
              <title>Project description</title>
              <description>Article: description of linked project written by editorial team</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project description</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/editorial</code>
              <title>CORDIS Editorial</title>
              <description>Written by CORDIS</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDIS Editorial</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </article>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedMasterCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedSubCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <organization source="corda" order="1" ecContribution="173847.36" terminated="false" sme="false" netEcContribution="173847.36" totalCost="0" type="coordinator">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1905689</rcn>
        <id>999978433</id>
        <vatNumber>DE811205325</vatNumber>
        <legalName>LUDWIG-MAXIMILIANS-UNIVERSITAET MUENCHEN</legalName>
        <shortName>LMU MUENCHEN</shortName>
        <address>
          <street>GESCHWISTER SCHOLL PLATZ  1</street>
          <city>MUNCHEN</city>
          <postalCode>80539</postalCode>
          <country>DE</country>
          <postBox>000</postBox>
          <url>http://www.uni-muenchen.de</url>
          <geolocation>48.15055845,11.5798871545463</geolocation>
        </address>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="organizationActivityType" type="relatedOrganizationActivityType">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/HES</code>
              <title>Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <regions>
            <region type="relatedNutsCode">
              <name>München, Kreisfreie Stadt</name>
              <rcn>221782082</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE212</nutsCode>
              <parents>
                <region>
                  <name>Oberbayern</name>
                  <rcn>221782120</rcn>
                  <nutsCode>DE21</nutsCode>
                  <parents>
                    <region>
                      <name>Bayern</name>
                      <rcn>221784616</rcn>
                      <nutsCode>DE2</nutsCode>
                      <parents>
                        <region>
                          <name>Germany</name>
                          <rcn>221940264</rcn>
                          <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
                          <euCode>DE</euCode>
                          <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
                        </region>
                      </parents>
                    </region>
                  </parents>
                </region>
              </parents>
            </region>
            <region type="relatedRegion">
              <name>Germany</name>
              <rcn>221940264</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
              <euCode>DE</euCode>
              <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
            </region>
          </regions>
        </relations>
      </organization>
      <programme source="corda" type="relatedTopic">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>706003</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON_HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</id>
        <code>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <title>MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships 2021</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>20300</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON-Topics</code>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/topic</code>
              <title>Topic</title>
              <description>Programme: Part of the Commission work programme implementing legal basis</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Topic</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <programme source="corda" uniqueProgrammePart="true" type="relatedLegalBasis">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>705729</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON.1.2</id>
        <code>HORIZON.1.2</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <pga>HORIZON.1.2</pga>
        <title>Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA)</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>705726</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON.1</code>
            <parent>
              <programme>
                <rcn>705725</rcn>
                <code>HORIZON</code>
              </programme>
            </parent>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/legalbasis</code>
              <title>Legal Basis</title>
              <description>Programme: Legal basis for research funding</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Legal Basis</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1292352</rcn>
        <id>101066396_1_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Data Management Plan</title>
        <description>The data obtained in this proposal will include the characterization of electrodes, the motion of robots, and the identification of the reaction’s products (e.g., H2). These records will consist of electronic data and video files obtained through custom software. They will be managed in line with the FAIR principles (Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, Reusable), and will be published in open access repositories e.g., Re3Data and Open Data LMU. If inventions are made, access to the data will be granted upon request once appropriate invention disclosures and/or provisional patent filings are made. I will use the research data management organizer (RDMO) tool offered by the LMU to generate a data management plan (DMP) that will be submitted after 6 months. I will also use this tool to track and update my DMP. I will receive guidance/support for data management and open science practices from RDM Information Center and Open Science Center at LMU library, respectively.</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-05-08 08:14:26</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-05-13 09:45:27</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/R</code>
              <title>Documents, reports</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Documents, reports</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
              <id>35bf03cc12114eae457eb4cb4e8f9c05</id>
              <physUrl><![CDATA[https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e51ba8b8b0&appId=PPGMS]]></physUrl>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1298848</rcn>
        <id>101066396_PSHORIZON</id>
        <title>Periodic Reporting for period 1 - PLOBOT (Autonomous Plasmon-Enhanced Photocatalytic Microrobots Powered by Lorentz Force)</title>
        <teaser>The PLOBOT project focused on developing light-driven plasmonic microrobots for precise motion control and enhanced photocatalysis. These microrobots integrate plasmonic and catalytic nanostructures, allowing for autonomous movement and efficient reaction kinetics under light...</teaser>
        <description>periodic</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-05-12 12:20:42</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-05-12 12:20:42</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/pubsum</code>
              <title>Report Summary</title>
              <description>Result: Publishable summary (FP7 SESAM) and Summary for publication (H2020 SyGMa)</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Report Summary</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1292356</rcn>
        <id>101066396_3_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title><![CDATA[Communication, Dissemination & Outreach Plan]]></title>
        <description>The dissemination plan of this action is aimed at specialized audiences (researchers) within the fields of nanoplasmonics, microrobots, photoelectrochemistry and materials science (including sub-fields), targeting universities and research institutes. Measures for result dissemination include: •Attending a conference to communicate early results regarding the use of photoactive materials in Lorentz force-driven microrobots (e.g., Microrobots and Nanorobots Nature Conferences).•Delivering a presentation at one of the Host Institution’s weekly seminars targeting a general academic audience to talk about microrobots in environmental remediation and energy generation.•Open-access publication of a high-impact paper showing results of plasmonic Lorentz force-driven microrobots.•Presenting results regarding the correlation of plasmonic effects on the exerted Lorentz force at the Fraunhofer Institute for Solar Energy Systems (ISE).•Disseminating results related to the HER efficiency of the plasmon-enhanced photoactive Lorentz force-driven microrobots, e.g., at the International Conference on Advances in Microrobotics (ICAM) in Zürich.•Delivering a talk about the development of solar-to-energy microrobots at the e-Conversion center in Munich. and at the German Federation for applied Photocatalysis (FAP).•Disseminating the results obtained on the photocatalytic efficiency of these robots towards hydrogen production and organic dye degradation via an open-access publication of a research paper and attending the International Conference on Applications of Microrobotics in New York. To set effective channels for result dissemination across these targeted audiences, a project website (“PLOBOT”) will be created to make it easier for the scientific audience and stakeholders to follow the project’s results during the fellowship. The idea behind disseminating results within research institutes through the plan talks listed above is to establish collaborations that would generate further advance in the research after the fellowship. To maximize visibility, the research output of this action will be published in high-impact journals that support open-access research and/or facilitate accessibility through pre-prints in repositories. The research outcomes of this action are expected to primarily contribute to fundamental knowledge gain in the microrobot field. The project will motivate further research in integrating other types of stimuli-responsive materials to trigger the Lorentz force-driven motion, such as enzymes and infrared-absorbing structures, and to translate the resulting electron transfer into sensing with electrochromic materials, for example. Thus, the results are envisioned to be non-commercially exploitable. However, in the long range, should the results lead to a promising energy conversion strategy, I will take on the following exploitation measures at the end of/after the fellowship:•Use of social media (LinkedIn and Twitter) to expose the project’s aims and results to potential stakeholders. In particular, I will actively seek to connect with start-ups that harvest solar-powered photocatalysis and/or hydrogen production micro-/nanotechnologies: US-based start-ups Syzygy Plasmonics, who use a nanotechnology-based plasmonic photocatalytic chemical reactor to generate valuable chemicals, and SunHydrogen, which use a nanoparticle-based patented system, “Photoelectrosynthetically Active Heterostructures”, to produce hydrogen from sunlight; and the Hungarian start-up Resysten, who develop a protective photocatalytic coating against organic and bacterial contamination.•With the help of LMU’s media resources, a general overview of how the technology works through videos, interviews and/or press releases, will be efficiently channeled in LMU’s online news section and shared via LinkedIn and Twitter to attract stakeholders’ attention and for public engagement.•The potential f</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-05-08 08:14:26</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-05-13 09:45:28</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/R</code>
              <title>Documents, reports</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Documents, reports</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
              <id>1d4f3e7c7453c67bdfd16b0b0272999b</id>
              <physUrl><![CDATA[https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e51ba8d037&appId=PPGMS]]></physUrl>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1293136</rcn>
        <id>101066396_152298_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>Polyoxometalates‐Mediated Selectivity in Pt Single‐Atoms on Ceria for Environmental Catalysis</title>
        <details>
          <authors>Tianwei Lan, Rambabu Yalavarthi, Yongjie Shen, Min Gao, Fuli Wang, Qingmin Hu, Pengfei Hu, Mohsen Beladi‐Mousavi, Xin Chen, Xiaonan Hu, Huiqian Yang, Emiliano Cortés, Dengsong Zhang</authors>
          <journalNumber>64</journalNumber>
          <journalTitle>Angewandte Chemie International Edition</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages/>
          <publishedYear>2025</publishedYear>
          <publisher>Wiley</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <doi>10.1002/ANIE.202415786</doi>
          <issn>1433-7851</issn>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-05-08 08:14:26</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-05-12 14:17:03</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
    </associations>
    <categories>
      <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/project</code>
        <title>Project</title>
        <description>Project factsheets</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/53/373</code>
        <title>electrochemistry</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/natural sciences/chemical sciences/electrochemistry</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/31/107/577/581/1393/1789</code>
        <title>science fiction</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/humanities/languages and literature/literature studies/literary genres/essays/science fiction</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/digitalAgenda</code>
        <title>Digital agenda</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development of digital technologies and the digitisation of the economy and society (known as ‘Digital transition’).</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Digital agenda</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/cleanAir</code>
        <title>Clean air</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the clean air policy (National Emission Ceiling Directive) aiming to improve ambient air quality and tackle air pollution, to protect the environment and human health.</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Clean air</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/ai</code>
        <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development and deployment of AI-based technologies and solutions. Projects that develop AI-tools as part of their research method are included</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Artificial intelligence</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/climate</code>
        <title>Climate action</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to both mitigating climate change (e.g., contributions to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions) and adapting to climate change by building resilience (e.g., regarding floods, droughts, spatial planning and better governance, adaptation to changing climate in value chains, etc.).</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Climate action</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/biodiversity</code>
        <title>Biodiversity</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to Europe’s biodiversity’s path to recovery including species protection, ecosystem conservation, and habitat rehabilitation, all essential for resilience in climate adaptation and addressing ecosystem services but also environmental crime and the health-environment connection.</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Biodiversity</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="projectFundingSchemeCategory" type="relatedProjectFundingSchemeCategory">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <code>/HORIZON-TMA-MSCA-PF-EF</code>
        <title>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</title>
        <description>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/corda</code>
        <title>CORDA</title>
        <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
      </category>
    </categories>
  </relations>
</project>
