<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <language>en</language>
  <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
  <rcn>239307</rcn>
  <id>101066785</id>
  <acronym>FishAdapt</acronym>
  <teaser>Global change is threatening life at the seas by changing the physical, chemical, and biological conditions of the environment. Thus, marine species will need to adapt to the new environmental conditions to thrive. This adaptation depends on the genetic variation within...</teaser>
  <objective>Global change is threatening life at the seas by changing the physical, chemical, and biological conditions of the environment. Thus, marine species will need to adapt to the new environmental conditions to thrive. This adaptation depends on the genetic variation within species, as it is the raw material on which natural selection works. Because environmental conditions at the sea are heterogeneous and most marine species are distributed across these diverse marine environments, it is likely that the genetic variation making possible the adaptation to changes in the environment is currently present within populations. Thus, the genetic flow among populations (or environments) can be one of the most important factors enabling adaptation to future environmental conditions in fish. However, harvesting fish populations is likely eroding their capacity to adapt to changes in the environment where they live. Thus, the goal of this study is to quantify the adaptive potential and likelihood of adaptation to environmental change in exploited fish populations, contributing with clear transferable knowledge to fisheries management strategies towards long-term sustainability. To do this we will use neutral and functional genetic variation data of two fish species from different environments presenting different degrees of exploitation. Potentially adaptive genetic variation will be revealed by looking for signals of both, adaptive and balancing selection among environments. Then, we will quantify the amount of potentially adaptive genetic variation and the effect of harvesting on it. Finally, we will investigate the strength of selection to get a likelihood of adaptation to future environmental change. Overall, the expected results of this study will set up theoretical and methodological frameworks for the evaluation of the current levels of adaptive potential for future environmental change in exploited fisheries.</objective>
  <title>Adaptive potential for changes in environmental conditions in exploited fish species.</title>
  <keywords>adaptive fisheries, evolution, natural selection, climate change, global change, genomics, adaptation, climate change, global change, genetic diversity, balancing selection</keywords>
  <totalCost>0</totalCost>
  <ecMaxContribution>165312.96</ecMaxContribution>
  <startDate>2022-07-01</startDate>
  <endDate>2024-06-30</endDate>
  <ecSignatureDate>2022-06-15</ecSignatureDate>
  <duration>24</duration>
  <status>CLOSED</status>
  <identifiers>
    <grantDoi>10.3030/101066785</grantDoi>
  </identifiers>
  <validation>
    <euroSciVoc>true</euroSciVoc>
  </validation>
  <sourceUpdateDate>2024-07-17 10:09:11</sourceUpdateDate>
  <contentCreationDate readOnly="true">2022-08-04 17:10:45</contentCreationDate>
  <contentUpdateDate>2022-08-04 17:10:42</contentUpdateDate>
  <lastUpdateDate readOnly="true">2025-09-19 14:48:52</lastUpdateDate>
  <relations>
    <associations>
      <article source="editorial" type="relatedArticle">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>434788</rcn>
        <id>434788-genetic-variation-could-help-some-fish-species-adapt</id>
        <title>Genetic variation could help some fish species adapt</title>
        <contentUpdateDate>2022-10-17 18:25:28</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/projectDescription</code>
              <title>Project description</title>
              <description>Article: description of linked project written by editorial team</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project description</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/editorial</code>
              <title>CORDIS Editorial</title>
              <description>Written by CORDIS</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDIS Editorial</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </article>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedMasterCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedSubCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <organization source="corda" order="1" ecContribution="165312.96" terminated="false" sme="false" netEcContribution="165312.96" totalCost="0" type="coordinator">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1905575</rcn>
        <id>999991722</id>
        <vatNumber>ESQ2818002D</vatNumber>
        <legalName>AGENCIA ESTATAL CONSEJO SUPERIOR DE INVESTIGACIONES CIENTIFICAS</legalName>
        <shortName>CSIC</shortName>
        <address>
          <street>CALLE SERRANO 117</street>
          <city>MADRID</city>
          <postalCode>28006</postalCode>
          <country>ES</country>
          <postBox>N/A</postBox>
          <url>http://www.csic.es</url>
          <geolocation>40.4409945,-3.6878876</geolocation>
        </address>
        <departmentName>Deputy Vice-Presidency for Scientific Programming</departmentName>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="organizationActivityType" type="relatedOrganizationActivityType">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/REC</code>
              <title>Research Organisations</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Research Organisations</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <regions>
            <region type="relatedNutsCode">
              <name>Madrid</name>
              <rcn>242233344</rcn>
              <nutsCode>ES300</nutsCode>
              <parents>
                <region>
                  <name>Comunidad de Madrid</name>
                  <rcn>242233384</rcn>
                  <nutsCode>ES30</nutsCode>
                  <parents>
                    <region>
                      <name>Comunidad de Madrid</name>
                      <rcn>242235944</rcn>
                      <nutsCode>ES3</nutsCode>
                      <parents>
                        <region>
                          <name>Spain</name>
                          <rcn>242387496</rcn>
                          <nutsCode>ES</nutsCode>
                          <euCode>ES</euCode>
                          <isoCode>ES</isoCode>
                        </region>
                      </parents>
                    </region>
                  </parents>
                </region>
              </parents>
            </region>
            <region type="relatedRegion">
              <name>Spain</name>
              <rcn>242387496</rcn>
              <nutsCode>ES</nutsCode>
              <euCode>ES</euCode>
              <isoCode>ES</isoCode>
            </region>
          </regions>
        </relations>
      </organization>
      <programme source="corda" type="relatedTopic">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>706003</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON_HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</id>
        <code>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <title>MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships 2021</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>20300</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON-Topics</code>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/topic</code>
              <title>Topic</title>
              <description>Programme: Part of the Commission work programme implementing legal basis</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Topic</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <programme source="corda" uniqueProgrammePart="true" type="relatedLegalBasis">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>705729</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON.1.2</id>
        <code>HORIZON.1.2</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <pga>HORIZON.1.2</pga>
        <title>Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA)</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>705726</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON.1</code>
            <parent>
              <programme>
                <rcn>705725</rcn>
                <code>HORIZON</code>
              </programme>
            </parent>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/legalbasis</code>
              <title>Legal Basis</title>
              <description>Programme: Legal basis for research funding</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Legal Basis</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>976580</rcn>
        <id>101066785_1_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Data Management Plan</title>
        <description>The overall methodology includes (1) the re-analysis of RADseq data previously obtained by the host research group to quantify the connectivity among environments and neutral genome-wide levels of genetic diversity, (2) the sequencing of samples of adult fish from three different environments (Galicia and Norway for both; Celtic Sea for ballan wrasse, L. bergylta, and Balearic Sea for the hake, M. merluccius) and larvae from one of these environments (Galicia) to survey genomic functional Single Nucleotide Polymorphism (SNPs) by using HTS technologies to reveal the adaptive potential to environmental conditions, and (3) performing different genomic and statistical analyses to produce quantifiable estimates of the adaptive potential (i.e. the resilience index) and the effect of harvesting on it, and then the likelihood of adaptation to changes in the environment. RADseq data will be analysed using R packages such as ipyrad, Bayescan, Arlequin version 3.5.2.2, DNAsp. Statistics such as Fst-index, number of migrants, and genetic distances will be used to estimate the amount of gene flow among populations. DNA-seq reads obtained from sequencing of functional genome regions, will be managed and analyzed using Genome Analysis Toolkit framework (GATK). We plan to study a minimum of 10 groups of functionally related genes (i.e. grouped by gene-pathways or gene ontology) including ~ 500-1000 coding genes (~ 2.5 -5% of coding genes in the genome). Sequencing will cover the whole coding length of genes and 1kb of sequences upstream of the transcription start site in order to get putative regulatory sequences. In total, we plan to produce sequences of functional genomic regions for ~150-180 adult samples (~75-90 by species) and 25-30 groups of larvae from different nests.  The Screening of potentially adaptive genetic variation will be performed using different approaches: a) Genomics seascape: We will use SamBada35 and related software to perform these analyses. b) Comparing allele frequencies of functional gene groups to neutral distributions and estimating statistics that are informative on the action of balancing selection. c) Random Forest algorithm can discover subtle changes in allele frequencies among environments than are undetectable using traditional population genetics approaches and we will use it as implemented in R packages. The deliverables of the project, as well as the designed pipelines for data analyses will be available for research and non-profit initiatives through the website of the project which will be created for this purpose within the institutional host web-service. Thus, the research proposal project will be connected to the DigitalCSIC data repository, which is also associated with other repositories (R3data, FAIRsharingData, etc) and Search platforms (Scholar google, etc) ensuring the correct dissemination and availability of the data, methods and results. Moreover, genomics sequences generated with this project will be deposit in public databases such as NCBI-bioproject database freely accessible for the whole scientific community.</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-06-27 13:12:24</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2023-09-29 11:56:45</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/DMP</code>
              <title>Data Management Plan</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Data Management Plan</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
              <id>029a3a3e7fa712826c2d2272f7199834</id>
              <physUrl><![CDATA[https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e50e50a102&appId=PPGMS]]></physUrl>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1123983</rcn>
        <id>101066785_3_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title><![CDATA[Communication, Dissemination & Outreach Plan]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Dissemination of the results of the project will be achieved by participating in scientific symposia and congresses, by peer-reviewed scientific publications, conferences, outreach talks, and by creating graphical material to distribute online through the web page of the host institutions and social media accounts. We have planned to participate in the following conferences, symposia and meetings, among others: ICES Annual Science Conference 2022 12-15 September 2022 Dublin, Ireland, where we will present Results of WP1 (D1); 5th International Symposium The Effects of Climate Change on the World’s Oceans. 17-21 April 2023 Bergen, Norway; where we will present the results of WP2 (D2); ASLO 2023 Aquatic Sciences Meeting. JUNE 4-9, 2023. Palma de Mallorca, Spain. where we will present the results of WP3 (D3); and ICES Annual Science Conference 2023 (~September); presenting results of WP4 (D4).The host institute, IIM-CSIC, has a strong commitment engaging Science with Society and a wide experience in education and outreach activities. The IIM-CSIC has its own Engagement with Society Unit (UCC+I) which works closely with the Scientific Culture Unit (UCC) of the CSIC's Delegation in Galicia, and will be able to give support to the dissemination and communication plan of this project through institutional web-pages and social media accounts. Moreover, the deliverables of the project will be available for research and non-profit initiatives through the IIM-CSIC website that is connected to the DigitalCSIC data repository, which is also associated with other repositories (R3data, FAIRsharingData, etc) and Search platforms (Scholar google, etc) ensuring the correct dissemination and availability of data and results.We will participate in outreach activities planned by the host institution and will produce graphical material to properly disseminate the FishAdapt project. Outreach activities are planned to be realized through the whole lifetime of the project fitting the Institution’s agenda. Outreach talks and graphical material will be addressed to different communities: 1) fishers: promoting sustainable fishing practices in relation to Climate Change adaptation; 2) governmental agencies and fisheries stakeholders: transferring the results and methodological approaches to influence decision-making policies in fisheries management; and 3) citizen in general as end-users/consumers: raising awareness on sustainable consumption of marine resources. Finally, the researcher candidate is committed to outreach and citizen sciences projects, and therefore she will disseminate the project goal and the research outputs through the lifetime of the project also through her personal twitter account @natpetit1.Given the high quality of the proposed research, we planned to submit two publications  with the results to high-impact journals relevant to the research field such as Global Change Biology, Fish and Fisheries, and Molecular Ecology. The submission of the Research Output (RO1) “adaptive potential to environmental change in exploited fish” is planned to be before the end of the first year of work (nearly April-May 2023);  while the submission of the RO2 is planned to be before the end of the second year (around April-May 2024). The two publications will be available first as pre-prints and then by open access publication, increasing their dissemination chances.]]></description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-06-25 18:13:45</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-07-01 14:07:27</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/R</code>
              <title>Documents, reports</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Documents, reports</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
              <id>73c3f39a439be47bab10777d4d57ba51</id>
              <physUrl><![CDATA[https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e50e2d7010&appId=PPGMS]]></physUrl>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1195236</rcn>
        <id>101066785_36288_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>State-of-the-art of data analyses in environmental DNA approaches towards its applicability to sustainable fisheries management</title>
        <details>
          <authors>Natalia Petit-Marty; Laura Casas; Fran Saborido-Rey</authors>
          <journalNumber/>
          <journalTitle>Frontiers in Marine Science</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages/>
          <publishedYear>2023</publishedYear>
          <publisher>Frontiers</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <doi>10.3389/fmars.2023.1061530</doi>
          <issn>2296-7745</issn>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-06-23 20:09:14</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-11-18 15:15:33</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1195220</rcn>
        <id>101066785_36287_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>Exploitation and Conservation Status of the Thornback Ray (Raja clavata) in the Balearic Islands (Western Mediterranean)</title>
        <details>
          <authors>Francesca Ferragut-Perello; Sergio Ramírez-Amaro; Athanassios C. Tsikliras; Natalia Petit-Marty; Donna Dimarchopoulou; Enric Massutí; Alba Serrat; Francesc Ordines</authors>
          <journalNumber/>
          <journalTitle>Fishes</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages/>
          <publishedYear>2023</publishedYear>
          <publisher>MDPI</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <doi>10.3390/fishes8020117</doi>
          <issn>2410-3888</issn>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-06-23 20:09:14</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-11-18 15:15:32</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1186127</rcn>
        <id>101066785_PSHORIZON</id>
        <title>Periodic Reporting for period 1 - FishAdapt (Adaptive potential for changes in environmental conditions in exploited fish species.)</title>
        <teaser>Environmental conditions are changing in oceans and seas. Thus, species inhabiting these habitats must adapt to the new environmental conditions. Genetic diversity is the raw material of natural selection allowing adaptation to environmental changes. However, exploited marine...</teaser>
        <description>periodic</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-11-04 15:49:38</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-11-11 12:06:16</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/pubsum</code>
              <title>Report Summary</title>
              <description>Result: Publishable summary (FP7 SESAM) and Summary for publication (H2020 SyGMa)</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Report Summary</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <associations>
            <webItem source="corda" type="relatedResultAttachment">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en,any</availableLanguages>
              <uri>/docs/results/horizon/101066/101066785_PS/fishadapt-summary.jpg</uri>
              <alternativeText>Summary of the background, main goal, methods, hypotheses (H) and main results of FISHADAPT</alternativeText>
              <mimetype readOnly="true">image/jpeg</mimetype>
              <size readOnly="true">275456</size>
            </webItem>
          </associations>
        </relations>
      </result>
    </associations>
    <categories>
      <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/project</code>
        <title>Project</title>
        <description>Project factsheets</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/27/81/489</code>
        <title>fisheries</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/agricultural sciences/agriculture, forestry, and fisheries/fisheries</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/49/337</code>
        <title>genetics</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/natural sciences/biological sciences/genetics</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/49/309/989</code>
        <title>molecular genetics</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/natural sciences/biological sciences/molecular biology/molecular genetics</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/25/67/11936537/64292513</code>
        <title>climate change adaptation</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/engineering and technology/environmental engineering/ecosystem-based management/climate change adaptation</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/49/345/1043</code>
        <title>ichthyology</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/natural sciences/biological sciences/zoology/ichthyology</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/digitalAgenda</code>
        <title>Digital agenda</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development of digital technologies and the digitisation of the economy and society (known as ‘Digital transition’).</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Digital agenda</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/cleanAir</code>
        <title>Clean air</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the clean air policy (National Emission Ceiling Directive) aiming to improve ambient air quality and tackle air pollution, to protect the environment and human health.</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Clean air</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/ai</code>
        <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development and deployment of AI-based technologies and solutions. Projects that develop AI-tools as part of their research method are included</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Artificial intelligence</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="40" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/climate</code>
        <title>Climate action</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to both mitigating climate change (e.g., contributions to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions) and adapting to climate change by building resilience (e.g., regarding floods, droughts, spatial planning and better governance, adaptation to changing climate in value chains, etc.).</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Climate action</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/biodiversity</code>
        <title>Biodiversity</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to Europe’s biodiversity’s path to recovery including species protection, ecosystem conservation, and habitat rehabilitation, all essential for resilience in climate adaptation and addressing ecosystem services but also environmental crime and the health-environment connection.</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Biodiversity</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="projectFundingSchemeCategory" type="relatedProjectFundingSchemeCategory">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <code>/HORIZON-TMA-MSCA-PF-EF</code>
        <title>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</title>
        <description>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/corda</code>
        <title>CORDA</title>
        <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
      </category>
    </categories>
  </relations>
</project>
