<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <language>en</language>
  <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
  <rcn>240498</rcn>
  <id>101066882</id>
  <acronym>engineereD to Clear</acronym>
  <teaser>Chronic lymphocytic leukemia is a common leukemia in adults characterized by an extremely immune suppressive microenvironment, which leads to the failure of otherwise effective immunotherapy regimens including dendritic cell (DC) based tumor vaccines. Recent attempts to...</teaser>
  <objective>Chronic lymphocytic leukemia is a common leukemia in adults characterized by an extremely immune suppressive microenvironment, which leads to the failure of otherwise effective immunotherapy regimens including dendritic cell (DC) based tumor vaccines. Recent attempts to understand immune suppression in CLL provided substantial evidence and identified that over-expression of amino acid catabolizing enzyme interleukin-4-induced 1 (IL4i1) in CLL and immune cells as key phenomenon in CLL mediated immune suppression. IL4i1 is secreted by DCs in the immune synapse and downregulates CD8+ T cell effector functions while presenting antigens, which perfectly explains failure of DC vaccines in CLL treatment. Addressing this, the important objectives of the present project are 1. To investigate the negative impacts of IL4i1 on DC functions, which are in particular relevance to DC vaccines and 2. To analyze the potential of IL4i1 deficient DCs in CLL vaccination. In this project I will first study ex vivo the DC and CD8+ T cell dysfunctions associated with DC secreted IL4i1 by assessing antigen presentation, immune synapse formation, CD8+ T cell activation and proliferation using both model antigen SIINFEKL and whole CLL cell antigens. Next, I will feed IL4i1 deficient DCs with whole CLL cell antigens and study using cutting-edge techniques their potential in eliciting anti-CLL immune responses in vivo using Eµ-TCL1 adaptively transferred CLL mouse model (TCL1AT).
I obtained my PhD in 2021 and presently working as research associate at the department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, University of Szeged, Hungary. I propose this project for Marie Curie postdoctoral fellowship- European fellowships. This project will be carried out in the division of Molecular Genetics, German Cancer Research Center (Deutsches Krebsforschungszentrum, DKFZ), Heidelberg, Germany under the supervision of Dr. Martina Seiffert.</objective>
  <title>Investigation on the vaccination potential of IL4i1 deficient dendritic cells in Chronic lymphocytic leukemia</title>
  <keywords>Chronic lymphocytic leukemia, Immune suppression, IL4i1, Aryl hydrocarbon receptor (AHR), Dendritic cells, DC vaccines, anti-tumoural immunity, cytotoxic T cells</keywords>
  <totalCost>0</totalCost>
  <ecMaxContribution>189687.36</ecMaxContribution>
  <startDate>2022-10-01</startDate>
  <endDate>2024-09-30</endDate>
  <ecSignatureDate>2022-07-28</ecSignatureDate>
  <duration>24</duration>
  <status>SIGNED</status>
  <identifiers>
    <grantDoi>10.3030/101066882</grantDoi>
  </identifiers>
  <validation>
    <euroSciVoc>true</euroSciVoc>
  </validation>
  <sourceUpdateDate>2025-01-03 10:47:16</sourceUpdateDate>
  <contentCreationDate readOnly="true">2022-09-02 16:00:25</contentCreationDate>
  <contentUpdateDate>2022-09-02 16:00:09</contentUpdateDate>
  <lastUpdateDate readOnly="true">2025-11-03 09:43:57</lastUpdateDate>
  <relations>
    <associations>
      <article source="editorial" type="relatedArticle">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>437656</rcn>
        <id>437656-molecular-insight-into-the-failure-of-dendritic-cell-vaccines-in-leukemia</id>
        <title>Molecular insight into the failure of dendritic cell vaccines in leukemia</title>
        <contentUpdateDate>2022-12-05 14:50:04</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/projectDescription</code>
              <title>Project description</title>
              <description>Article: description of linked project written by editorial team</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project description</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/editorial</code>
              <title>CORDIS Editorial</title>
              <description>Written by CORDIS</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDIS Editorial</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </article>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedMasterCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedSubCall">
        <rcn>55376</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <organization source="corda" order="1" ecContribution="189687.36" terminated="false" sme="false" netEcContribution="189687.36" totalCost="0" type="coordinator">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1906203</rcn>
        <id>999990073</id>
        <vatNumber>DE143293537</vatNumber>
        <legalName>DEUTSCHES KREBSFORSCHUNGSZENTRUM HEIDELBERG</legalName>
        <shortName>GERMAN CANCER RESEARCH CENTER</shortName>
        <address>
          <street>IM NEUENHEIMER FELD 280</street>
          <city>Heidelberg</city>
          <postalCode>69120</postalCode>
          <country>DE</country>
          <postBox>10 19 49</postBox>
          <url>http://www.dkfz.de</url>
          <geolocation>49.414429,8.6723675803449</geolocation>
        </address>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="organizationActivityType" type="relatedOrganizationActivityType">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/REC</code>
              <title>Research Organisations</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Research Organisations</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <regions>
            <region type="relatedNutsCode">
              <name>Heidelberg, Stadtkreis</name>
              <rcn>221778053</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE125</nutsCode>
              <parents>
                <region>
                  <name>Karlsruhe</name>
                  <rcn>221778088</rcn>
                  <nutsCode>DE12</nutsCode>
                  <parents>
                    <region>
                      <name>Baden-Württemberg</name>
                      <rcn>221780520</rcn>
                      <nutsCode>DE1</nutsCode>
                      <parents>
                        <region>
                          <name>Germany</name>
                          <rcn>221940264</rcn>
                          <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
                          <euCode>DE</euCode>
                          <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
                        </region>
                      </parents>
                    </region>
                  </parents>
                </region>
              </parents>
            </region>
            <region type="relatedRegion">
              <name>Germany</name>
              <rcn>221940264</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
              <euCode>DE</euCode>
              <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
            </region>
          </regions>
        </relations>
      </organization>
      <programme source="corda" type="relatedTopic">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>706003</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON_HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</id>
        <code>HORIZON-MSCA-2021-PF-01-01</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <title>MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships 2021</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>20300</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON-Topics</code>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/topic</code>
              <title>Topic</title>
              <description>Programme: Part of the Commission work programme implementing legal basis</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Topic</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <programme source="corda" uniqueProgrammePart="true" type="relatedLegalBasis">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>705729</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON.1.2</id>
        <code>HORIZON.1.2</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <pga>HORIZON.1.2</pga>
        <title>Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA)</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>705726</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON.1</code>
            <parent>
              <programme>
                <rcn>705725</rcn>
                <code>HORIZON</code>
              </programme>
            </parent>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/legalbasis</code>
              <title>Legal Basis</title>
              <description>Programme: Legal basis for research funding</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Legal Basis</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1256536</rcn>
        <id>101066882_3_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title><![CDATA[Communication, Dissemination & Outreach Plan]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[DKFZ strongly supports and help researchers engage in science outreach activities via several means, so I will take courses on communicating science (e.g. Science Communication & Outreach (training.institut-curie.org/courses/), Lets talk science (www.linkedin.com/company/let%27s-talk-science)) to convey science to the  general public and other target groups. As a Marie Sklodowska Curie Fellow I will actively engage and provide the public with insights into my research via science outreach activities organized by DKFZ (e.g. open seminars, collaboration with clinicians,internal research team meetings) and will volunteer in Teachers + Scientists which is aimed to educate teachers thereby, school students the research and advancements in cancer prevention and immunotherapy (www.dkfz.de/en/immuntherapie- immunpraevention/groups/outreach.html).  I will also promote science to encourageyoung aspirants through science fairs such as Berlin Science week (https://berlinscienceweek.com/). DKFZ works in close association with the University Clinic Heidelberg. I would avail this opportunity to participate to meet patientsand make them aware of new research in cancer therapy and management through oral and poster presentations and answering to their questions. During the project, the experimental outcomes will be discussed in regular internal research team meetings to provide updates on the progress of the project and receive constructive feedback andsuggestions from team members. All the single-cell transcriptomics data will be made available to the wide public through a database (e.g. scRNASeqDB (https://bioinfo.uth.edu/scrnaseqdb/)). Research findings from this project willbe disseminated through presentations at national and international meetings (ASH (American Society of Hematology) and EHA (European Hematology Association) meetings, iwCLL (International Workshop on CLL). Since the proposed project addresses important questions and has high potential for translation, the results will be published in high-impact journals (Immunity, Leukemia), in which the Martina Seiffert laboratory has published recently. The publications will be open access in accordance with the Horizon Europe open access policy. The present project aims to unravel the negative effects of IL4i1 on DC functions relevant in DC vaccines and investigates to establish IL4i1-/- DCs as potent candidates in DC vaccines to treat CLL. The proposed research, although has great translational potency, is an early discovery stage of the commercialization pipeline. Any intellectual property, material transfer agreements, issues around patent protected procedures and material related to this project  will be duly discussed and managed through the Innovation Management Office of DKFZ.]]></description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-02-17 20:05:29</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-02-26 08:02:41</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/R</code>
              <title>Documents, reports</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Documents, reports</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
              <id>c08d4a29f6a0d30827d86f259065ea67</id>
              <physUrl><![CDATA[https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e5189ecdfc&appId=PPGMS]]></physUrl>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1292291</rcn>
        <id>101066882_PSHORIZON</id>
        <title>Periodic Reporting for period 1 - engineereD to Clear (Investigation on the vaccination potential of IL4i1 deficient dendritic cells in Chronic lymphocytic leukemia)</title>
        <teaser>The primary objective of this project is to enhance the efficacy of dendritic cell (DC)-based immunotherapy by targeting the Il4i1 metabolic immune checkpoint. Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL) presents unique immunosuppressive challenges, making it imperative to identify and...</teaser>
        <description>periodic</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-05-08 08:14:26</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-05-08 08:14:26</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/pubsum</code>
              <title>Report Summary</title>
              <description>Result: Publishable summary (FP7 SESAM) and Summary for publication (H2020 SyGMa)</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Report Summary</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>975245</rcn>
        <id>101066882_1_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Data Management Plan</title>
        <description>Standard scientific software will be used to curate and analyze the generated data The space required for storage is estimated to be 1 TB All options of reusing preexisting open research data software algorithms or workflows will be examined carefully during the project Complete DMP will be submitted on 6th month of projects start and is updated regularly throughout the project duration Findability In addition to generic metadata elements also discipline compliant metadata elements will be used describing the data to aid discovery and potential reuse Persistent identifiers DOI or URN provided by the data repository will be generated and linked to datasets Accessibility Published and FAIRcompliant data will be archived in certified open data repositories to ensure longterm accessibility Interoperability Variables and value names will be constructed and provided in a logical manner common to the research field Common formats of stored datasets will be applied to ensure easy interoperability and reuse between different applications Reusability Reusability will be ensured by careful documentation of data contents and their acquisition methods CC BY 40 license will be used for any open datasets The opened data will be deposited in a repository that guarantees data integrity on bit level To manage the lifecycle of datasets collected processed or created throughout the project duration a Project Data Management Plan will be generated which will include a description of methodology and standards to be followed Data sets will be made accessible for verification and reuse after project closure</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2023-07-19 22:16:15</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2023-09-28 15:44:26</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/DMP</code>
              <title>Data Management Plan</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Data Management Plan</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" represents="project" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
              <id>7fdf31cb29aa7fe2346924c863fe8007</id>
              <physUrl><![CDATA[https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e5fa856e3d&appId=PPGMS]]></physUrl>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
        </relations>
      </result>
    </associations>
    <categories>
      <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/project</code>
        <title>Project</title>
        <description>Project factsheets</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/49/309/989</code>
        <title>molecular genetics</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/natural sciences/biological sciences/molecular biology/molecular genetics</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/21/35/159/653/1439</code>
        <title>vaccines</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/medical and health sciences/basic medicine/pharmacology and pharmacy/pharmaceutical drugs/vaccines</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/21/35/155/643</code>
        <title>immunotherapy</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/medical and health sciences/basic medicine/immunology/immunotherapy</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/21/39/225/719</code>
        <title>leukemia</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/medical and health sciences/clinical medicine/oncology/leukemia</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/digitalAgenda</code>
        <title>Digital agenda</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development of digital technologies and the digitisation of the economy and society (known as ‘Digital transition’).</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Digital agenda</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/cleanAir</code>
        <title>Clean air</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the clean air policy (National Emission Ceiling Directive) aiming to improve ambient air quality and tackle air pollution, to protect the environment and human health.</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Clean air</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/ai</code>
        <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development and deployment of AI-based technologies and solutions. Projects that develop AI-tools as part of their research method are included</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Artificial intelligence</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/climate</code>
        <title>Climate action</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to both mitigating climate change (e.g., contributions to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions) and adapting to climate change by building resilience (e.g., regarding floods, droughts, spatial planning and better governance, adaptation to changing climate in value chains, etc.).</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Climate action</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/biodiversity</code>
        <title>Biodiversity</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to Europe’s biodiversity’s path to recovery including species protection, ecosystem conservation, and habitat rehabilitation, all essential for resilience in climate adaptation and addressing ecosystem services but also environmental crime and the health-environment connection.</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Biodiversity</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="projectFundingSchemeCategory" type="relatedProjectFundingSchemeCategory">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <code>/HORIZON-TMA-MSCA-PF-EF</code>
        <title>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</title>
        <description>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/corda</code>
        <title>CORDA</title>
        <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
      </category>
    </categories>
  </relations>
</project>
