<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <language>en</language>
  <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
  <rcn>256776</rcn>
  <id>101093572</id>
  <acronym>StarDance</acronym>
  <teaser>Thanks to their ubiquity, brightness, and the fact that they are made of stars with similar properties, star clusters have been used as astrophysical laboratories or test particles in an impressive range of research domains. However, we still do not understand fundamental...</teaser>
  <objective>Thanks to their ubiquity, brightness, and the fact that they are made of stars with similar properties, star clusters have been used as astrophysical laboratories or test particles in an impressive range of research domains. However, we still do not understand fundamental details of their formation and evolution. In spite of recent technological progress, a list of unsolved problems and apparently isolated mysteries has been accumulating over time, some standing since decades.

Among them, the existence of multiple stellar populations in globular clusters, with different chemistry, has challenged generations of researchers. They are not the result of classical galactic chemical evolution, mostly mediated by supernovae, and they jeopardize the use of clusters as simple stellar population templates for extragalactic studies.

Given the mounting problems faced by the most favored scenarios to explain multiple populations, I think it is now time to revisit the foundations of our current thinking. New results by my team and by others show that: (i) the peculiarities in the chemistry of multiple populations are not limited to the oldest globular clusters; (ii) they can be transient in the evolution of individual cluster stars; and most importantly (iii) binary interactions and fast stellar rotation cannot be neglected in the study of star clusters and do have the capability to produce the observed chemistry.

With StarDance I will test a very different scenario, based on a new hypothesis: that multiple stellar populations and five other non-canonical stellar populations (extreme horizontal branch stars and hot sub-dwarfs; extended main sequence turn-offs; red stragglers and sub-subgiants; lithium rich- stars; and blue stragglers) are caused by the interplay between stellar rotation and binary interactions, that are greatly enhanced in the special environment of star cluster, with spectacular results.</objective>
  <title>StarDance: the non-canonical evolution of stars in clusters</title>
  <keywords>techniques: spectroscopic, surveys, stars: abundances, stars: binaries, stars: rotation, Galaxy: globular clusters, Galaxy: open clusters and associations, Galaxy: abundances</keywords>
  <totalCost>2492250</totalCost>
  <ecMaxContribution>2492250</ecMaxContribution>
  <startDate>2023-11-01</startDate>
  <endDate>2028-10-31</endDate>
  <ecSignatureDate>2023-08-24</ecSignatureDate>
  <duration>60</duration>
  <status>SIGNED</status>
  <identifiers>
    <grantDoi>10.3030/101093572</grantDoi>
  </identifiers>
  <validation>
    <euroSciVoc>false</euroSciVoc>
  </validation>
  <sourceUpdateDate>2025-01-03 10:47:16</sourceUpdateDate>
  <contentCreationDate readOnly="true">2023-09-08 15:00:09</contentCreationDate>
  <contentUpdateDate>2023-09-08 14:59:05</contentUpdateDate>
  <lastUpdateDate readOnly="true">2025-11-03 09:43:26</lastUpdateDate>
  <relations>
    <associations>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedMasterCall">
        <rcn>55593</rcn>
        <title>ERC-2022-ADG</title>
        <identifier>ERC-2022-ADG</identifier>
      </call>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedSubCall">
        <rcn>55593</rcn>
        <title>ERC-2022-ADG</title>
        <identifier>ERC-2022-ADG</identifier>
      </call>
      <organization source="corda" order="1" ecContribution="2492250" terminated="false" sme="false" netEcContribution="2492250" totalCost="2492250" type="coordinator">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1906922</rcn>
        <id>999868920</id>
        <vatNumber>IT06895721006</vatNumber>
        <legalName>ISTITUTO NAZIONALE DI ASTROFISICA</legalName>
        <shortName>INAF</shortName>
        <address>
          <street>VIALE DEL PARCO MELLINI 84</street>
          <city>ROMA</city>
          <postalCode>00136</postalCode>
          <country>IT</country>
          <postBox>000</postBox>
          <url>http://www.inaf.it</url>
          <geolocation>41.9233386,12.4520256</geolocation>
        </address>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="organizationActivityType" type="relatedOrganizationActivityType">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/REC</code>
              <title>Research Organisations</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Research Organisations</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <regions>
            <region type="relatedNutsCode">
              <name>Roma</name>
              <rcn>1464004</rcn>
              <nutsCode>ITI43</nutsCode>
              <parents>
                <region>
                  <name>Lazio</name>
                  <rcn>1465012</rcn>
                  <nutsCode>ITI4</nutsCode>
                  <parents>
                    <region>
                      <name>Centro (IT)</name>
                      <rcn>1465008</rcn>
                      <nutsCode>ITI</nutsCode>
                      <parents>
                        <region>
                          <name>Italy</name>
                          <rcn>309758504</rcn>
                          <nutsCode>IT</nutsCode>
                          <euCode>IT</euCode>
                          <isoCode>IT</isoCode>
                        </region>
                      </parents>
                    </region>
                  </parents>
                </region>
              </parents>
            </region>
            <region type="relatedRegion">
              <name>Italy</name>
              <rcn>309758504</rcn>
              <nutsCode>IT</nutsCode>
              <euCode>IT</euCode>
              <isoCode>IT</isoCode>
            </region>
          </regions>
        </relations>
      </organization>
      <programme source="corda" type="relatedTopic">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>706725</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON_ERC-2022-ADG</id>
        <code>ERC-2022-ADG</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <title>ERC ADVANCED GRANTS</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>20300</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON-Topics</code>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/topic</code>
              <title>Topic</title>
              <description>Programme: Part of the Commission work programme implementing legal basis</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Topic</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <programme source="corda" uniqueProgrammePart="true" type="relatedLegalBasis">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>705727</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON.1.1</id>
        <code>HORIZON.1.1</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <pga>HORIZON.1.1</pga>
        <title>European Research Council (ERC)</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>705726</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON.1</code>
            <parent>
              <programme>
                <rcn>705725</rcn>
                <code>HORIZON</code>
              </programme>
            </parent>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/legalbasis</code>
              <title>Legal Basis</title>
              <description>Programme: Legal basis for research funding</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Legal Basis</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1335093</rcn>
        <id>101093572_169300_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title><![CDATA[Discovery of a dormant 33 solar-mass black hole in pre-release <i>Gaia</i> astrometry]]></title>
        <details>
          <authors>null, null; Panuzzo, P.; Mazeh, T.; Arenou, F.; Holl, B.; Caffau, E.; Jorissen, A.; Babusiaux, C.; Gavras, P.; Sahlmann, J.; Bastian, U.; Wyrzykowski, Ł.; Eyer, L.; Leclerc, N.; Bauchet, N.; Bombrun, A.; Mowlavi, N.; Seabroke, G. M.; Teyssier, D.; Balbinot, E.; Helmi, A.; Brown, A. G. A.; Vallenari, A.; Prusti, T.; de Bruijne, J. H. J.; Barbier, A.; Biermann, M.; Creevey, O. L.; Ducourant, C.; Evans, D. W.; Guerra, R.; Hutton, A.; Jordi, C.; Klioner, S. A.; Lammers, U.; Lindegren, L.; Luri, X.; Mignard, F.; Nicolas, C.; Randich, S.; Sartoretti, P.; Smiljanic, R.; Tanga, P.; Walton, N. A.; Aerts, C.; Bailer-Jones, C. A. L.; Cropper, M.; Drimmel, R.; Jansen, F.; Katz, D.; Lattanzi, M. G.; Soubiran, C.; Thévenin, F.; van Leeuwen, F.; Andrae, R.; Audard, M.; Bakker, J.; Blomme, R.; Castañeda, J.; De Angeli, F.; Fabricius, C.; Fouesneau, M.; Frémat, Y.; Galluccio, L.; Guerrier, A.; Heiter, U.; Masana, E.; Messineo, R.; Nienartowicz, K.; Pailler, F.; Riclet, F.; Roux, W.; Sordo, R.; Gracia-Abril, G.; Portell, J.; Altmann, M.; Benson, K.; Berthier, J.; Burgess, P. W.; Busonero, D.; Busso, G.; Cacciari, C.; Cánovas, H.; Carrasco, J. M.; Carry, B.; Cellino, A.; Cheek, N.; Clementini, G.; Damerdji, Y.; Davidson, M.; de Teodoro, P.; Delchambre, L.; Dell'Oro, A.; Fraile Garcia, E.; Garabato, D.; García-Lario, P.; Haigron, R.; Hambly, N. C.; Harrison, D. L.; Hatzidimitriou, D.; Hernández, J.; Hestroffer, D.; Hodgkin, S. T.; Jamal, S.; Jevardat de Fombelle, G.; Jordan, S.; Krone-Martins, A.; Lanzafame, A. C.; Löffler, W.; Lorca, A.; Marchal, O.; Marrese, P. M.; Moitinho, A.; Muinonen, K.; Nuñez Campos, M.; Oreshina-Slezak, I.; Osborne, P.; Pancino, E.; Pauwels, T.; Recio-Blanco, A.; Riello, M.; Rimoldini, L.; Robin, A. C.; Roegiers, T.; Sarro, L. M.; Schultheis, M.; Smith, M.; Sozzetti, A.; Utrilla, E.; van Leeuwen, M.; Weingrill, K.; Abbas, U.; Ábrahám, P.; Abreu Aramburu, A.; Ahmed, S.; Altavilla, G.; Álvarez, M. A.; Anders, F.; Anderson, R. I.; Anglada Varela, E.; Antoja, T.; Baig, S.; Baines, D.; Baker, S. G.; Balaguer-Núñez, L.; Balog, Z.; Barache, C.; Barros, M.; Barstow, M. A.; Bartolomé, S.; Bashi, D.; Bassilana, J. -L.; Baudeau, N.; Becciani, U.; Bedin, L. R.; Bellas-Velidis, I.; Bellazzini, M.; Beordo, W.; Bernet, M.; Bertolotto, C.; Bertone, S.; Bianchi, L.; Binnenfeld, A.; Blanco-Cuaresma, S.; Bland-Hawthorn, J.; Blazere, A.; Boch, T.; Bossini, D.; Bouquillon, S.; Bragaglia, A.; Braine, J.; Bratsolis, E.; Breedt, E.; Bressan, A.; Brouillet, N.; Brugaletta, E.; Bucciarelli, B.; Butkevich, A. G.; Buzzi, R.; Camut, A.; Cancelliere, R.; Cantat-Gaudin, T.; Capilla Guilarte, D.; Carballo, R.; Carlucci, T.; Carnerero, M. I.; Carretero, J.; Carton, S.; Casamiquela, L.; Casey, A.; Castellani, M.; Castro-Ginard, A.; Ceraj, L.; Cesare, V.; Charlot, P.; Chaudet, C.; Chemin, L.; Chiavassa, A.; Chornay, N.; Chosson, D.; Cooper, W. J.; Crosta, M.; Crowley, C.; Cruz Reyes, M.; Dafonte, C.; Dal Ponte, M.; David, M.; de Laverny, P.; De Luise, F.; De March, R.; Delbo, M.; Delisle, J. -B.; Dharmawardena, T. E.; Di Giacomo, F.; Distefano, E.; Dsilva, K.; Enke, H.; Fabrizio, M.; Faigler, S.; Fatović, M.; Fedorets, G.; Fernique, P.; Figueras, F.; Fragkoudi, F.; Gai, M.; Galinier, M.; García-Torres, M.; Garofalo, A.; Gerlach, E.; Geyer, R.; Giacobbe, P.; Gilmore, G.; Girona, S.; Giuffrida, G.; Gomboc, A.; Gomez, A.; González-Santamaría, I.; Granvik, M.; Gutiérrez-Sánchez, R.; Haywood, M.; Hidalgo, S. L.; Hilger, T.; Hobbs, D.; Hottier, C.; Jiménez-Arranz, Ó.; Kaczmarek, Z.; Kervella, P.; Khanna, S.; Kontizas, M.; Kordopatis, G.; Korn, A. J.; Kóspál, Á; Kruszyńska, K.; Kun, M.; Lambert, S.; Lanza, A. F.; Lebreton, Y.; Lebzelter, T.; Leccia, S.; Liao, S.; Liberato, L.; Licata, E.; Livanou, E.; Lobel, A.; López-Miralles, J.; Madarász, M.; Mahy, L.; Mann, R. G.; Manteiga, M.; Marcellino, C. P.; Marchant, J. M.; Marconi, M.; Marín Pina, D.; Marinoni, S.; Marshall, D. J.; Martín Lozano, J.; Martí</authors>
          <journalNumber/>
          <journalTitle>Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages/>
          <publishedYear>2024</publishedYear>
          <publisher>EDP Sciences</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <doi>10.48550/ARXIV.2404.10486</doi>
          <issn>1432-0746</issn>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-06-20 12:24:34</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-07-18 11:35:22</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1335078</rcn>
        <id>101093572_169298_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>Differential reddening in 48 globular clusters: An end to the quest for the intracluster medium</title>
        <details>
          <authors>Pancino, E.; Zocchi, A.; Rainer, M.; Monaci, M.; Massari, D.; Monelli, M.; Hunt, L. K.; Monaco, L.; Martínez-Vázquez, C. E.; Sanna, N.; Bianchi, S.; Stetson, P. B.</authors>
          <journalNumber/>
          <journalTitle>Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages/>
          <publishedYear>2024</publishedYear>
          <publisher>EDP Sciences</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <doi>10.48550/ARXIV.2404.05548</doi>
          <issn>1432-0746</issn>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-06-20 12:24:34</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-07-18 11:35:18</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result source="corda" type="relatedResult">
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1335070</rcn>
        <id>101093572_169299_PUBLIHORIZON</id>
        <title>SpectroTranslator: Deep-neural network algorithm for homogenising spectroscopic parameters</title>
        <details>
          <authors>G. F. Thomas; G. Battaglia; F. Gran; E. Fernández-Alvar; M. Tsantaki; E. Pancino; V. Hill; G. Kordopatis; C. Gallart; A. Turchi; T. Masseron</authors>
          <journalNumber/>
          <journalTitle>Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics</journalTitle>
          <publishedPages/>
          <publishedYear>2024</publishedYear>
          <publisher>EDP Sciences</publisher>
        </details>
        <identifiers>
          <doi>10.48550/ARXIV.2404.02578</doi>
          <issn>1432-0746</issn>
        </identifiers>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-06-20 12:24:34</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-07-18 11:35:15</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/publication</code>
              <title>Project publication</title>
              <description>Result: Project publications</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project publication</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="projectPublication" type="isPublishedAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/PEER_REVIEWED_ARTICLE</code>
              <title>Peer reviewed articles</title>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/Peer reviewed articles</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
    </associations>
    <categories>
      <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/project</code>
        <title>Project</title>
        <description>Project factsheets</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Project</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/53/365/78089026</code>
        <title>alkali metals</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/natural sciences/chemical sciences/inorganic chemistry/alkali metals</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/23/43/257/757/1483</code>
        <title>supernova</title>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/natural sciences/physical sciences/astronomy/stellar astronomy/supernova</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="40" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/digitalAgenda</code>
        <title>Digital agenda</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development of digital technologies and the digitisation of the economy and society (known as ‘Digital transition’).</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Digital agenda</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/cleanAir</code>
        <title>Clean air</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the clean air policy (National Emission Ceiling Directive) aiming to improve ambient air quality and tackle air pollution, to protect the environment and human health.</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Clean air</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/ai</code>
        <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development and deployment of AI-based technologies and solutions. Projects that develop AI-tools as part of their research method are included</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Artificial intelligence</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/climate</code>
        <title>Climate action</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to both mitigating climate change (e.g., contributions to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions) and adapting to climate change by building resilience (e.g., regarding floods, droughts, spatial planning and better governance, adaptation to changing climate in value chains, etc.).</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Climate action</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category weight="0" classification="policyPriorities" type="marker">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/biodiversity</code>
        <title>Biodiversity</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to Europe’s biodiversity’s path to recovery including species protection, ecosystem conservation, and habitat rehabilitation, all essential for resilience in climate adaptation and addressing ecosystem services but also environmental crime and the health-environment connection.</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/Biodiversity</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="projectFundingSchemeCategory" type="relatedProjectFundingSchemeCategory">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">en</availableLanguages>
        <code>/HORIZON-ERC</code>
        <title>HORIZON ERC Grants</title>
        <description>HORIZON ERC Grants</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/HORIZON ERC Grants</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages readOnly="true">de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/corda</code>
        <title>CORDA</title>
        <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
        <displayCode readOnly="true">/CORDA</displayCode>
      </category>
    </categories>
  </relations>
</project>
