<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
  <language>en</language>
  <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
  <rcn>255178</rcn>
  <id>101103025</id>
  <acronym>ECODEM</acronym>
  <teaser>In the aftermath of the First World War, European cities witnessed a massive expansion of producer cooperatives in the building sector. Drawing on ideas for industrial reform that were shared widely across borders, these producer cooperatives, or building guilds, aimed to not...</teaser>
  <objective>In the aftermath of the First World War, European cities witnessed a massive expansion of producer cooperatives in the building sector. Drawing on ideas for industrial reform that were shared widely across borders, these producer cooperatives, or building guilds, aimed to not only improve urban housing, but also democratize the construction industries and society more broadly. Local cooperatives quickly merged into national associations that promoted distinct models of collective decision-making and shared ownership. By the early 1920s, pan-European federations had started to distribute information and organize exchange between construction cooperatives that stretched the entire continent. Despite their rapid growth and initial success, however, the construction cooperatives of interwar Europe have been virtually forgotten. ECODEM offers the first comprehensive historical analysis of this transnational movement. Focusing on England, Germany, and Spain, the action has the following four objectives. First, it will reveal the democratization measures that were implemented to improve participation on the shop floor, at the work site, and in management. Second, it will show what urban vision this trade union movement formulated, and how this vision compares with the urban vision of architect, planners, and municipal officials, which have received far more attention in scholarship. Third, ECODEM will investigate under what conditions employees accepted measures aiming at rationalization, even if those measures had negative consequences for labor. And fourth, it will analyze the factors that determined success and failure of construction cooperatives in distinct national settings. By studying a forgotten yet highly popular trade union movement, ECODEM not only advances scholarship in Labor and Urban History as well as the interdisciplinary scholarship on economic democracy, but it also contributes to debates in the wider public about the future of work and urban housing.</objective>
  <title>The Building Guilds of Interwar Europe: An Experiment in Economic Democracy</title>
  <totalCost>0</totalCost>
  <ecMaxContribution>189687.36</ecMaxContribution>
  <startDate>2023-10-01</startDate>
  <endDate>2025-09-30</endDate>
  <ecSignatureDate>2023-04-24</ecSignatureDate>
  <duration>24</duration>
  <status>SIGNED</status>
  <keywords>Labor History, Urban History, Interwar Europe, Trade Unions, Economic Democracy, History of Housing</keywords>
  <identifiers>
    <grantDoi>10.3030/101103025</grantDoi>
  </identifiers>
  <validation>
    <euroSciVoc>false</euroSciVoc>
  </validation>
  <sourceUpdateDate>2024-12-31 09:30:22</sourceUpdateDate>
  <contentCreationDate>2023-07-25 19:55:57</contentCreationDate>
  <contentUpdateDate>2023-07-25 19:55:30</contentUpdateDate>
  <lastUpdateDate>2025-09-19 14:48:59</lastUpdateDate>
  <relations>
    <associations>
      <article source="editorial" type="relatedArticle">
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>446472</rcn>
        <id>446472-shedding-light-on-europe-s-construction-cooperatives</id>
        <title>Shedding light on Europe’s construction cooperatives</title>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-02-02 09:38:30</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/projectDescription</code>
              <title>Project description</title>
              <description>Article: description of linked project written by editorial team</description>
              <displayCode>/Project description</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/editorial</code>
              <title>CORDIS Editorial</title>
              <description>Written by CORDIS</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDIS Editorial</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </article>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedMasterCall">
        <rcn>55393</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <call source="corda" type="relatedSubCall">
        <rcn>55393</rcn>
        <title>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01</title>
        <identifier>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01</identifier>
      </call>
      <organization netEcContribution="189687.36" totalCost="0" source="corda" order="1" ecContribution="189687.36" terminated="false" sme="false" type="coordinator">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1905653</rcn>
        <id>999986678</id>
        <vatNumber>DE811231089</vatNumber>
        <legalName>TECHNISCHE UNIVERSITAT BERLIN</legalName>
        <shortName>TUB</shortName>
        <address>
          <street>STRASSE DES 17 JUNI 135</street>
          <city>Berlin</city>
          <postalCode>10623</postalCode>
          <country>DE</country>
          <postBox>000</postBox>
          <url>http://www.tu-berlin.de</url>
          <geolocation>52.5121106,13.32700630032475</geolocation>
        </address>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="organizationActivityType" type="relatedOrganizationActivityType">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/HES</code>
              <title>Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</title>
              <displayCode>/Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <regions>
            <region type="relatedNutsCode">
              <name>Berlin</name>
              <rcn>221786112</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE300</nutsCode>
              <parents>
                <region>
                  <name>Berlin</name>
                  <rcn>221786152</rcn>
                  <nutsCode>DE30</nutsCode>
                  <parents>
                    <region>
                      <name>Berlin</name>
                      <rcn>221788712</rcn>
                      <nutsCode>DE3</nutsCode>
                      <parents>
                        <region>
                          <name>Germany</name>
                          <rcn>221940264</rcn>
                          <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
                          <euCode>DE</euCode>
                          <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
                        </region>
                      </parents>
                    </region>
                  </parents>
                </region>
              </parents>
            </region>
            <region type="relatedRegion">
              <name>Germany</name>
              <rcn>221940264</rcn>
              <nutsCode>DE</nutsCode>
              <euCode>DE</euCode>
              <isoCode>DE</isoCode>
            </region>
          </regions>
        </relations>
      </organization>
      <organization netEcContribution="0" totalCost="0" source="corda" order="2" terminated="false" sme="false" type="associatedPartner">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1910033</rcn>
        <id>999976202</id>
        <vatNumber>ESQ0818003F</vatNumber>
        <legalName>UNIVERSITAT POLITECNICA DE CATALUNYA</legalName>
        <shortName>UPC</shortName>
        <address>
          <street>CALLE JORDI GIRONA 31</street>
          <city>BARCELONA</city>
          <postalCode>08034</postalCode>
          <country>ES</country>
          <postBox>000</postBox>
          <url>http://www.upc.edu</url>
          <geolocation>41.3825596,2.1771353</geolocation>
        </address>
        <departmentName>Technology Transfer Centre</departmentName>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="organizationActivityType" type="relatedOrganizationActivityType">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/HES</code>
              <title>Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</title>
              <displayCode>/Higher or Secondary Education Establishments</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
          <regions>
            <region type="relatedNutsCode">
              <name>Barcelona</name>
              <rcn>242241601</rcn>
              <nutsCode>ES511</nutsCode>
              <parents>
                <region>
                  <name>Cataluña</name>
                  <rcn>242241640</rcn>
                  <nutsCode>ES51</nutsCode>
                  <parents>
                    <region>
                      <name>Este</name>
                      <rcn>242244136</rcn>
                      <nutsCode>ES5</nutsCode>
                      <parents>
                        <region>
                          <name>Spain</name>
                          <rcn>242387496</rcn>
                          <nutsCode>ES</nutsCode>
                          <euCode>ES</euCode>
                          <isoCode>ES</isoCode>
                        </region>
                      </parents>
                    </region>
                  </parents>
                </region>
              </parents>
            </region>
            <region type="relatedRegion">
              <name>Spain</name>
              <rcn>242387496</rcn>
              <nutsCode>ES</nutsCode>
              <euCode>ES</euCode>
              <isoCode>ES</isoCode>
            </region>
          </regions>
        </relations>
      </organization>
      <programme type="relatedLegalBasis" source="corda" uniqueProgrammePart="true">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>705729</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON.1.2</id>
        <code>HORIZON.1.2</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <pga>HORIZON.1.2</pga>
        <title>Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA)</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>705726</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON.1</code>
            <parent>
              <programme>
                <rcn>705725</rcn>
                <code>HORIZON</code>
              </programme>
            </parent>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/legalbasis</code>
              <title>Legal Basis</title>
              <description>Programme: Legal basis for research funding</description>
              <displayCode>/Legal Basis</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <programme type="relatedTopic" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>706018</rcn>
        <id>HORIZON_HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01-01</id>
        <code>HORIZON-MSCA-2022-PF-01-01</code>
        <frameworkProgramme>HORIZON</frameworkProgramme>
        <title>MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships 2022</title>
        <parent>
          <programme>
            <rcn>20300</rcn>
            <code>HORIZON-Topics</code>
          </programme>
        </parent>
        <relations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/topic</code>
              <title>Topic</title>
              <description>Programme: Part of the Commission work programme implementing legal basis</description>
              <displayCode>/Topic</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </programme>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1102540</rcn>
        <id>101103025_1_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Data Management Plan</title>
        <description>Data consists of published sources (periodicals, newspapers, magazines, reports, and independent publications) as well as unpublished archival material (such as minute books, letters, manuscripts, press clippings, and bylaws). Archival sources will be made publicly available to the extent that archives give consent. Article pre-prints will be shared on DepositOnce, TU Berlin’s open access repository, and linked to other academic repositories such as Academia.edu and ResearchGate. The researcher will produce a databank with summaries of all consulted sources. The databank together with all publications and any other output by this action will be stored on DepositOnce. The researcher will be supported by TU Berlin’s Service Center Research Data Management (SZF) as well as the Open Access Advisory Services unit at TU Berlin Library.</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2024-06-08 11:34:04</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2024-06-10 10:03:54</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
              <id>6ef9957521dec027f0d2ac4dc3f164cd</id>
              <physUrl>https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e50b529fa0&amp;appId=PPGMS</physUrl>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode>/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/DMP</code>
              <title>Data Management Plan</title>
              <displayCode>/Data Management Plan</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
      <result type="relatedResult" source="corda">
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <rcn>1349914</rcn>
        <id>101103025_3_DELIVHORIZON</id>
        <title>Communication, Disseminatio and Exploitation Plan</title>
        <description>Dissemination measures:- two research articles that will be submitted to prestigious peer-reviewed journals. The first article will be dedicated to Objective 2. Co-authored with the supervisor, the paper will improve our understanding of the vision for urban space and housing the building guilds formulated. The paper will be submitted to the journal Urban History, which will ensure dissemination among urban historians. The second article will be dedicated to Objective 3. It will analyze the conditions under which construction workers in the past embraced processes of rationalization in their everyday work environment. It will be submitted to the journal Labor History, which will help disseminate research findings among labor historians. Both articles will, as all other publications whenever possible, be published in Open Access.- two papers presented at the European Social Science History Conference (ESSHC) and the European Association for Urban History (EAUH) respectively. The first paper will present findings about Objective 1; the second paper will present findings about Objective 4. The papers will show how historical-empirical research contributes to scholarship on economic democracy, and what conditions contributed to the success of cooperative construction in the past. ESSHC and EAUH are ideal formats for interdisciplinary dissemination as they bring together urban and social historians with historically interested scholars from the social sciences. - a monograph on the building guilds of interwar Europe, with a focus on England, Germany, and Spain. The monograph will be the main output of this action. The ER will propose the manuscript for publication in the Palgrave MacMillan’s Studies in the History of Social Movements series. The measure targets students and researchers in Urban History, Labor History, Social History, Political Theory, and Social Movement Studies.- a presentation of the research design at CMS colloquium (beginning of funding period). This measure serves to make researchers at the host and at other institutions in Berlin aware of ECODEM.- an international interdisciplinary workshop on “The Past and Present of Economic Democracy in Metropolitan Context”, co-organized together with Prof. Oyón Bañales, the supervisor during the secondment phase. Results will be published in a co-edited volume after the end of the funding period. The main objective of the workshop is to make the topic of the action more visible and to build new as well as strengthen existing research cooperation and networks.Exploitation measures:- a public evening discussion (two-way exchange). The event will be organized together with a local trade union body and a local housing cooperative. The goal of this event is to show how historical research contributes to a better understanding of democratic participation today and, in so doing, how History contributes to strengthening civil society. In particular, the measure aims to present past initiatives for democratic participation in co-operative and trade-union settings, thereby providing examples that might contribute to current debates by stakeholders. The measure targets policy makers, academics, trade union members, housing co-operatives and the general public. The event will be advertised in local media. Based on experiences, it will reach a live audience of about 30–40 people. Communication activities:- a Facebook Page targeting historians, social scientist, archivists, librarians, members of cooperatives and housing associations, trade unionist, and members of the public (two-way exchange). The page will be set up by the ER after an initial two-month period of source gathering and layout work. It will be maintained beyond the end of the funding period. The page will feature bi-weekly postings of archival finds, and it will announce all measures for dissemination, exploitation, and communication. The page aims to make the project more visible, facilitate excha</description>
        <sourceUpdateDate>2025-08-25 08:12:51</sourceUpdateDate>
        <contentUpdateDate>2025-08-25 08:12:51</contentUpdateDate>
        <relations>
          <associations>
            <webLink source="corda" type="projectDeliverable">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
              <id>fad54d4346693b46dcd129b8ba0c8c7d</id>
              <physUrl>https://ec.europa.eu/research/participants/documents/downloadPublic?documentIds=080166e520fe0bf7&amp;appId=PPGMS</physUrl>
              <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
            </webLink>
          </associations>
          <categories>
            <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/deliverable</code>
              <title>Project deliverable</title>
              <description>Result: Project deliverables</description>
              <displayCode>/Project deliverable</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="deliverableType" type="isDeliveredAs">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/R</code>
              <title>Documents, reports</title>
              <displayCode>/Documents, reports</displayCode>
            </category>
            <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
              <language>en</language>
              <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
              <code>/corda</code>
              <title>CORDA</title>
              <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
              <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
            </category>
          </categories>
        </relations>
      </result>
    </associations>
    <categories>
      <category classification="collection" type="belongsTo">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/project</code>
        <title>Project</title>
        <description>Project factsheets</description>
        <displayCode>/Project</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/31/113/613/30035</code>
        <title>modern history</title>
        <displayCode>/humanities/history and archaeology/history/modern history</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="euroSciVoc" type="isInFieldOfScience">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/29/97/543/1337</code>
        <title>democracy</title>
        <displayCode>/social sciences/political sciences/government systems/democracy</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="40">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/digitalAgenda</code>
        <title>Digital agenda</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development of digital technologies and the digitisation of the economy and society (known as ‘Digital transition’).</description>
        <displayCode>/Digital agenda</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="40">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/cleanAir</code>
        <title>Clean air</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the clean air policy (National Emission Ceiling Directive) aiming to improve ambient air quality and tackle air pollution, to protect the environment and human health.</description>
        <displayCode>/Clean air</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="40">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/ai</code>
        <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to the development and deployment of AI-based technologies and solutions. Projects that develop AI-tools as part of their research method are included</description>
        <displayCode>/Artificial intelligence</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="40">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/climate</code>
        <title>Climate action</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to both mitigating climate change (e.g., contributions to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions) and adapting to climate change by building resilience (e.g., regarding floods, droughts, spatial planning and better governance, adaptation to changing climate in value chains, etc.).</description>
        <displayCode>/Climate action</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="policyPriorities" type="marker" weight="0">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/biodiversity</code>
        <title>Biodiversity</title>
        <description>This tracker monitors the Horizon Europe’s financial contribution to Europe’s biodiversity’s path to recovery including species protection, ecosystem conservation, and habitat rehabilitation, all essential for resilience in climate adaptation and addressing ecosystem services but also environmental crime and the health-environment connection.</description>
        <displayCode>/Biodiversity</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="projectFundingSchemeCategory" type="relatedProjectFundingSchemeCategory">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>en</availableLanguages>
        <code>/HORIZON-TMA-MSCA-PF-EF</code>
        <title>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</title>
        <description>HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</description>
        <displayCode>/HORIZON TMA MSCA Postdoctoral Fellowships - European Fellowships</displayCode>
      </category>
      <category classification="source" type="isProvidedBy">
        <language>en</language>
        <availableLanguages>de,en,es,fr,it,pl</availableLanguages>
        <code>/corda</code>
        <title>CORDA</title>
        <description>RTD research data warehouse</description>
        <displayCode>/CORDA</displayCode>
      </category>
    </categories>
  </relations>
</project>